<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cultural distance | Andreas Genoni</title>
    <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/tag/cultural-distance/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://a-genoni.github.io/tag/cultural-distance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Cultural distance</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://a-genoni.github.io/media/icon_hu36d72c3cf6f96053b96f9b849fe00da0_28466_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Cultural distance</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/tag/cultural-distance/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is it all about the costs? Cultural distance and adjustment of recent migrants</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/current-work/genoni-et-al-2023-is-it-all-about-costs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/current-work/genoni-et-al-2023-is-it-all-about-costs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cultural distance (CD) between the origin and destination country of migrants has long been considered important for individual adjustment. Past research predominantly followed a cost perspective, emphasising rising adjustment costs with increasing CD and postulating a negative linear relationship. Previous studies therefore overlooked potential benefits of CD for adjustment. We address this gap by taking a more differentiated perspective on CD and adjustment. Using probability-based survey data on recent German migrants , we examined migrant adjustment at different CD-levels. Employing multilevel regressions for sociocultural and psychological adjustment, the findings reveal an inverted-U shaped relationship between CD and both adjustment dimensions. This challenges the cost perspective, indicating an “optimal” range of intermediate CD as most beneficial for adjustment. Thus, the prevailing view on negative consequences of CD for adjustment may underestimate the challenges for culturally close migrants, and overlook that certain levels of cultural dissimilarity can facilitate migrants’ adjustment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;Suggested citation:&lt;/strong&gt; Genoni, A.; Décieux, J. P.; Murdock, E. (2023). Is it all about the costs? Cultural distance and adjustment of recent migrants. &lt;em&gt;SocArXiv&lt;/em&gt;. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.31235/osf.io/uskq9&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.31235/osf.io/uskq9&lt;/a&gt;.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cultural distance and adaptation</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/project/cultural-contact-in-migration-contexts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/project/cultural-contact-in-migration-contexts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Culture can be considered a relatively stable trait of adult individuals because important parts of personality already form during adolescence. Most individuals emigrate in their adulthood, which means their cultural traits are less malleable once they start living abroad. Cultural differences to non-immigrants therefore become relatively constant distances immigrants have to deal with. Thus, it is important to better understand what role cultural distances play in adapting to a new environment, with increasing time spent abroad, and how immigrants can cope with related challenges. In this project, you will find personal work on these topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;related-work&#34;&gt;Related work&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2023 | &lt;span style=&#34;color:#93003a&#34;&gt;Is it all about the costs? Cultural distance and adjustment of recent migrants&lt;/span&gt; | with Jean Philippe Décieux and Elke Murdock | &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.31235/osf.io/uskq9&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Preprint&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work in progress | &lt;span style=&#34;color:#93003a&#34;&gt;Expatriate adjustment and the role of cultural distance&lt;/span&gt; | with Jean Philippe Décieux and Heiko Rüger
&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work in progress | &lt;span style=&#34;color:#93003a&#34;&gt;Between cultural proximity and distance: Understanding the role of cultural distance for perceived ostracism&lt;/span&gt; | with Selma Rudert, Jean Philippe Décieux, Elianne Albath and Christiane Büttner&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
