<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Andreas Genoni</title>
    <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://a-genoni.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Andreas Genoni</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://a-genoni.github.io/media/icon_hu36d72c3cf6f96053b96f9b849fe00da0_28466_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Andreas Genoni</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Session on well-being in population research</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2023-07-09-session-on-well-being/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2023-07-09-session-on-well-being/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The session was opened by its chair Katharina Spieß, who introduced the speakers (picture).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bib.bund.de/EN/Institute/Staff/Stawarz/Stawarz.html;jsessionid=CA1C73D7435F153D69470FF104799585.intranet662&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Nico Stawarz&lt;/a&gt; gave a great introductory keynote on why we need to go beyond GDP and other
&amp;ldquo;objective&amp;rdquo; measures of quality of/inequalities in life, and also look on the well-being
of populations. He thereby revealed parts of the progressive research agenda that the BiB will pursue in
the years ahead: Monitoring the well-being of the German population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The highlight were three key notes from &lt;a href=&#34;https://population-europe.eu/network/expert-portraits/mynarska&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Monika Mynarska&lt;/a&gt; (Cardinal Stefan Wyszyński University in Warsaw), &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.martijnhendriks.net/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Martijn Hendriks&lt;/a&gt; (Erasmus University Rotterdam) and &lt;a href=&#34;https://psych.ubc.ca/profile/eric-kim/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Eric Kim&lt;/a&gt; (University of British Columbia), leading scientists in the fields of family, migration, and aging. They provided us with an overview of state-of-the-art research on well-being from their discipline&amp;rsquo;s perspective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks again to all speakers and the organisers! This really was food for thought.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does international migration make people happy?</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2023-07-07-migration-and-swb/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2023-07-07-migration-and-swb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I gave a lightning talk at the BiB&amp;rsquo;s Turning Gold conference about &lt;strong&gt;shifts in subjective well-being in the course of international migration&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;mdash;a study with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bib.bund.de/EN/Institute/Staff/Stawarz/Stawarz.html;jsessionid=CA1C73D7435F153D69470FF104799585.intranet662&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Nico Stawarz&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bib.bund.de/DE/Institut/Mitarbeiter/Ette/Ette.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Andreas Ette&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bib.bund.de/DE/Institut/Mitarbeiter/Rueger/Rueger.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Heiko Rüger&lt;/a&gt; (all BiB).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using unique longitudinal data that includes actual migration events (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gerps-project.de/gerps/EN/Home.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GERPS&lt;/a&gt;), we find robust evidence that the subjective well-being of internationally mobile individuals increases notably with their move abroad (picture).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Round table on dataviz in policy relevant research</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2020-07-06-dataviz-round-table/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2020-07-06-dataviz-round-table/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;what-makes-good-dataviz-for-policy-relevant-research&#34;&gt;What makes good dataviz for policy relevant research?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data visualisation plays an important role in communicating research to others. This is especially the
case in policy-making processes, where researchers want to avoid misinterpretation of empirical evidence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;knowing-our-stuff&#34;&gt;Knowing our stuff&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Participants agreed that for being able to communicate research through visualisations,
researchers first have to understand what they are doing. This may seem like a no-brainer but
researchers have to make themselves familiar with the data they are working with, and,
depending on the discipline, with the mechanisms that contribute to the observed patterns in the data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Researchers are responsible for their products, and responsibility can best be borne by knowledgeable people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;finding-the-middle-ground&#34;&gt;Finding the middle ground&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The challenge that most participants of the round table addressed was to deal
with trade-offs between simplicity and complexity. Policy makers want numbers
to quantify things but a single number often provides incomplete information of complex
relationships in the data. Dataviz helps to attach more information to numbers but
visualising data properly takes more time&amp;mdash;and time is a limited resource in policy-making processes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High hopes, high disappointment?</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2023-06-15-shp-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2023-06-15-shp-conference/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;what-happens-when-expectations-of-immigrants-about-live-abroad-do-not-meet-with-their-experiences&#34;&gt;What happens when expectations of immigrants about live abroad do not meet with their experiences?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I gave a talk about how unmet migration expectations influence the lives of immigrants. I started this work together with &lt;a href=&#34;https://druedin.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Didier Ruedin&lt;/a&gt; (University of Neuchâtel) last winter during my research stay at the Swiss National Center of Competence in Research (NCCR) on Migration and Mobility Studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using panel data of the Migration-Mobility Survey (MMS), we observed that unmet migration expectations hit harder on immigrants with tertiary education than immigrants with non-tertiary education. We found robust evidence for comparably stronger perceptions of discrimination (picture) and increased emotional disengagement with Switzerland. Stay tuned for the paper.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysing and visualising human migration</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/project/human-migration/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/project/human-migration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This project features personal work on human migration and mobility from a macro perspective. I study  patterns and trends in various forms of spatial mobility in order to reveal interdependencies between them, and to better understand population dynamics. For this purpose, parts of my work are explicitly dedicated to the visualisation of human migration flows by using circular migration plots. Circular migration plots are a viable alternative to conventional flow maps and other existing visualisations of migration flows. They are an effective and visually appealing method for visualising flow data because they allow the reader to quickly identify key patterns and trends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will find guidance and code that help you create your own circular migration plots in the context of &amp;ldquo;The Global Flow of People 2.0&amp;rdquo; project and the handbook article listed below. Don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to contact me if you have any further questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;related-work&#34;&gt;Related work&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Forthcoming | &lt;span style=&#34;color:#93003a&#34;&gt;The Global Flow of People 2.0.&lt;/span&gt; &amp;mdash; An interactive application that visualises global human migration over the past 30 years | with Nikola Sander, Tamilwai Kolowa, Tina Frank, and Clemens Schrammel
&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2023 | &lt;span style=&#34;color:#93003a&#34;&gt;Who moves where? Global Migration Flows between 2015-2020&lt;/span&gt; &amp;mdash; A poster of international migration flows between the top-50 countries with the largest volume of migration | with Nikola Sander, Tamilwai Kolowa, Tina Frank, and Clemens Schrammel | &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/KunstuniLinzViskom&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PDF (available in English and German)&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Forthcoming | &lt;span style=&#34;color:#93003a&#34;&gt;Data visualisation in migration research. The case of circular migration plots.&lt;/span&gt; In Vargas-Silva, C. &amp;amp; Allen, W. (Eds.). Handbook of Research Methods in Migration. Second edition. Edward Elgar Publishing | with Nikola Sander
&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work in progress | &lt;span style=&#34;color:#93003a&#34;&gt;How have commuting, internal and international migration  changed over time? A trend study of three mobilities using German Microcensus data&lt;/span&gt; | with Nico Stawarz, Heiko Rüger, Andreas Ette, Thomas Skora, Matthias Rosenbaum-Feldbrügge, and Nikola Sander
&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2021 | &lt;span style=&#34;color:#93003a&#34;&gt;Globale Bevölkerungsentwicklung. Fakten und Trends.&lt;/span&gt; BiB.Bevölkerungs.Studien 1/2021. Wiesbaden: BiB | &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bib.bund.de/Publikation/2021/Globale-Bevoelkerungsentwicklung.html?nn=1219558&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cultural distance and adaptation</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/project/cultural-contact-in-migration-contexts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/project/cultural-contact-in-migration-contexts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Culture can be considered a relatively stable trait of adult individuals because important parts of personality already form during adolescence. Most individuals emigrate in their adulthood, which means their cultural traits are less malleable once they start living abroad. Cultural differences to non-immigrants therefore become relatively constant distances immigrants have to deal with. Thus, it is important to better understand what role cultural distances play in adapting to a new environment, with increasing time spent abroad, and how immigrants can cope with related challenges. In this project, you will find personal work on these topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;related-work&#34;&gt;Related work&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work in progress | &lt;span style=&#34;color:#93003a&#34;&gt;Cultural distance and immigrant adjustment&lt;/span&gt; | with Jean Philippe Décieux and Elke Murdock | &lt;a href=&#34;https://a-genoni.github.io/current-work/cd-and-adjustment/&#34;&gt;more info&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work in progress | &lt;span style=&#34;color:#93003a&#34;&gt;Expatriate adjustment and the role of cultural distance&lt;/span&gt; | with Jean Philippe Décieux and Heiko Rüger&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cultural distance and immigrant adjustment</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/current-work/cd-and-adjustment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/current-work/cd-and-adjustment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cultural distance (CD) between the country of origin and destination
country of migrants has long been considered important for adjustment in
international migration. Past research has mainly followed a cost perspective,
pointing to rising costs in adjustment with increasing CD, postulating a negative
linear relationship. Following this logic, previous studies overlooked potential
benefits of CD for adjustment. We address this gap by taking a more differentiated
perspective on CD and adjustment. Using unique probability-based survey data on
German migrants in 38 destination countries with a maximum length of
stay of 36 months, we examined different CD-levels and their consequences for
adjustment. We ran multilevel regressions for sociocultural and psychological
adjustment. Importantly, our findings indicate that the CD effect on adjustment
is not linear but clearly resembles an inverted-U shape for both adjustment
dimensions. This result challenges the cost perspective and suggests an “optimal”
range of intermediate CD as most beneficial for recent migrants’ adjustment. We
conclude that the prevailing view on the consequences of CD for migrant adjustment
holds true for very large CDs, but it underestimates the challenges for culturally
close migrants and overlooks that a certain level of cultural dissimilarity can
facilitate migrants’ adjustment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Individual consequences of international migration</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/project/consequences-of-international-migration/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/project/consequences-of-international-migration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A question that I am particularly interested in is how international migration impacts the lives of immigrants. This question is a tough one, because it is one of cause and effect and requires unique data to address it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, it is not sufficient to compare individuals after their move abroad with non-migrated individuals in their home country, because differences between these groups may be the result of specific characteristics of the individuals within the two groups. If we imagine that migration can be a stressful life event, individuals who move abroad might be healthier and more resilient than individuals who stay put, because migration would otherwise not be feasible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, if researchers would find physical and mental health advantages among migrants, it would be unclear whether they made this discovery because migrants are genuinely healthier and happier, or because migration itself may have contributed to their increased health and happiness. By the way, the thought of migration as a potentially positive life event is not far-fetched at all, because migration may not only be stressful but also open up individual opportunities to develop and thrive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apparently, addressing the question of cause and effect of migration places an extremely high demand on data. They have to be longitudinal and must include actual migration events. This enables researchers to observe individuals before, during and after their move abroad, and to compare these different stages with each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But how can researchers find and survey individuals who &lt;strong&gt;will&lt;/strong&gt; move abroad during the time of a planned panel survey? Unless researchers are blessed with foresight, they have to come up with a promising strategy. Luckily, my colleagues at the BiB did so. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gerps-project.de/gerps/EN/Project/Project.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;German Emigration and Remigration Panel Study (GERPS)&lt;/a&gt; meets these high data demands. Following Germans who shortly moved abroad or returned to Germany before the survey started, we collected data of a internationally highly mobile population with a high probability of being internationally mobile again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The work listed below is based on these unique data. It aims to tighten the boundaries of causal inference by shedding light on the actual consequences of international migration for immigrants&amp;rsquo; lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;related-work&#34;&gt;Related work&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work in progress | &lt;span style=&#34;color:#93003a&#34;&gt;International migration and the subjective well-being of internationally mobile individuals&lt;/span&gt; | with Nico Stawarz, Andreas Ette, and Heiko Rüger | &lt;a href=&#34;https://a-genoni.github.io/current-work/mig-and-swb/&#34;&gt;more info&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International migration and subjective well-being</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/current-work/mig-and-swb/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/current-work/mig-and-swb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In many economically highly-developed countries, a relevant proportion
of the population migrates across national boundaries every year. For these
individuals, migrating abroad not only comes with advantages (e.g. monetary
returns) but also with potential pitfalls, because migration is accompanied by
profound changes in everyday life. However, only few and mainly cross-sectional
studies about individuals’ migration expierences exist, analysing the effects
of migration on their quality of life. This study addresses these lacunae and
investigates shifts in subjective well-being (SWB) of internationally mobile
German citizens. We apply fixed effects (FE) panel regression models to data of
the German Emigration and Remigration Panel Study (GERPS). To observe SWB in
the course of migration, we draw on a sample of repeat migrants—Germans who
returned to Germany shortly before the panel and migrated again across international
borders during the panel. As counterfactuals, we focus on Germans who returned
to Germany shortly before the panel but stayed there. Overall life satisfaction
is used as an SWB-indicator, which corresponds to a global assessment of one’s
life situation. In sum, our analyses reveal a happiness dip before migration as
well as an increased and relatively stable SWB at the pre-migration baseline
level in the first two years after migration.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The paradox of integration</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/project/paradox-of-integration/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/project/paradox-of-integration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Research and regular monitors about the integration of immigrants has typically looked at &amp;ldquo;objective&amp;rdquo; indicators of integration such as education, stable employment, language skills or income. In the past years, however, increasingly more attention has been given to the &amp;ldquo;inner life&amp;rdquo; of immigrants, referring to more &amp;ldquo;subjective&amp;rdquo; indicators of integration such as their emotional attachment to the new home, their feelings of belongingness to its society or their perceptions of discrimination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the continued publication of empirical studies on immigrants&amp;rsquo; subjective integration, an integration paradox has been revealed: Many of those immigrants who seem integrated in terms of their education or occupational status do not feel that they are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such a misalignment can be problematic because it may increase the likelihood of frustration, mental health issues, and emigration. But the seemingly better integrated are particularly valuable for receiving societies because they can play an important role in helping new arrivals to participate and incorporate into the institutions of the mainstream society. Furthermore, they are more efficiently deployable in the local labour market and less at risk from unemployment. These issues are particularly pressing in times when many developed countries face labour shortages and compete for talents globally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project bundles personal work on the integration paradox. It looks at different factors and mechanisms that contribute to this paradox, and tries to better understand the potential issues and consequences related to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;related-work&#34;&gt;Related work&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2022 | &lt;span style=&#34;color:#93003a&#34;&gt;Status and Ethnic Identity. A Study on First- and Second-Generation Migrants in Germany.&lt;/span&gt; Verlag Barbara Budrich | &lt;a href=&#34;https://a-genoni.github.io/publication/genoni-2022-status-and-ethnic-identity/&#34;&gt;publication&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work in progress | &lt;span style=&#34;color:#93003a&#34;&gt;Unmet migration expectations and their consequences for the lives of immigrants&lt;/span&gt; | with Didier Ruedin | &lt;a href=&#34;https://a-genoni.github.io/current-work/expectations-and-attachment/&#34;&gt;more info&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unmet migration expectations and their consequences for the lives of immigrants</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/current-work/expectations-and-attachment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/current-work/expectations-and-attachment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Migration research suggests that higher educated migrants report weaker
attachment to their destination country than their lower-educated counterparts.
This so-called integration paradox is probably caused by higher educated migrants
perceiving more discrimination in ambiguous or unfavourable situations. Here we
examine unmet expectations migrants have about their life abroad, experience of
discrimination, and how these account for educational differences in destination
attachment. We use cross-sectional and panel data of recent migrants to Switzerland
from the Swiss Migration-Mobility Survey, capturing unmet expectations with a
question on dissatisfaction with the migration decision. In line with the integration
paradox, we observe lower destination attachment among higher educated migrants
with unmet expectations. Although they more often report discrimination, this
does not explain their lower destination attachment within this group. Instead
of discrimination, adaptation problems matter. Higher educated migrants with unmet
expectations do not outperform their lower-educated counterparts on other integration
dimensions, particularly in social terms. These results indicate that migrants
do not necessarily link unmet expectations to discrimination. Migrants may be
optimistic and particularly vulnerable to disappointment but they can also mitigate
more detrimental consequences, because they are prepared for moving into an unfamiliar
environment despite lacking locally important resources.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Status and Ethnic Identity. A Study on First- and Second-Generation Migrants in Germany</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/publication/genoni-2022-status-and-ethnic-identity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/publication/genoni-2022-status-and-ethnic-identity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;Suggested Citation:&lt;/strong&gt; Genoni, A. (2022). &lt;em&gt;Status and Ethnic Identity. A Study on First- and Second-Generation Migrants in Germany.&lt;/em&gt; Verlag Barbara Budrich. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3224/84742575&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3224/84742575&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Internationale Mobilität und Sozialstruktur</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/publication/ette-et-al-2021-internationale-mobilitat/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/publication/ette-et-al-2021-internationale-mobilitat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;Suggested citation:&lt;/strong&gt; Ette, A., Genoni, A., &amp;amp; Witte, N. (2021). Internationale Mobilität und Sozialstruktur. In Federal Statistical Office, Berlin Social Science Center and Federal Institute for Population Research (Eds.), &lt;em&gt;Datenreport 2021. Ein Sozialbericht für die Bundesrepublik Deutschland&lt;/em&gt; (pp. 316–323). Bundeszentrale für politische Bildung.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Status transition in the educational system and well-being of migrant adolescents in cross-national comparison</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/publication/nauck-genoni-2019-status-transition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/publication/nauck-genoni-2019-status-transition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Suggested Citation:
Nauck, B., Genoni, A. (2019). Status transition in the educational system and well-being of migrant adolescents in cross-national comparison. &lt;em&gt;Zeitschrift für Erziehungswissenschaft 22&lt;/em&gt;(S1), 47–69. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/s11618-019-00887-z&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/s11618-019-00887-z&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slides</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/slides/example/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/slides/example/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;create-slides-in-markdown-with-wowchemy&#34;&gt;Create slides in Markdown with Wowchemy&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Wowchemy&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/content/slides/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;features&#34;&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Efficiently write slides in Markdown&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3-in-1: Create, Present, and Publish your slides&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supports speaker notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mobile friendly slides&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;controls&#34;&gt;Controls&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Next: &lt;code&gt;Right Arrow&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;Space&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Previous: &lt;code&gt;Left Arrow&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start: &lt;code&gt;Home&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finish: &lt;code&gt;End&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overview: &lt;code&gt;Esc&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Speaker notes: &lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fullscreen: &lt;code&gt;F&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Zoom: &lt;code&gt;Alt + Click&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://revealjs.com/pdf-export/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PDF Export&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;code-highlighting&#34;&gt;Code Highlighting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inline code: &lt;code&gt;variable&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Code block:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34; data-lang=&#34;python&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;porridge&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;blueberry&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;porridge&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;==&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;blueberry&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;    &lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;print&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;Eating...&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;math&#34;&gt;Math&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In-line math: $x + y = z$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Block math:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$$
f\left( x \right) = ;\frac{{2\left( {x + 4} \right)\left( {x - 4} \right)}}{{\left( {x + 4} \right)\left( {x + 1} \right)}}
$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fragments&#34;&gt;Fragments&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make content appear incrementally&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;{{% fragment %}} One {{% /fragment %}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;{{% fragment %}} **Two** {{% /fragment %}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;{{% fragment %}} Three {{% /fragment %}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Press &lt;code&gt;Space&lt;/code&gt; to play!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;fragment &#34; &gt;
  One
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;fragment &#34; &gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;Two&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;fragment &#34; &gt;
  Three
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A fragment can accept two optional parameters:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;class&lt;/code&gt;: use a custom style (requires definition in custom CSS)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;weight&lt;/code&gt;: sets the order in which a fragment appears&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;speaker-notes&#34;&gt;Speaker Notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add speaker notes to your presentation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34; data-lang=&#34;markdown&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;{{% speaker_note %}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; Only the speaker can read these notes
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; Press &lt;span class=&#34;sb&#34;&gt;`S`&lt;/span&gt; key to view
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;  {{% /speaker_note %}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Press the &lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt; key to view the speaker notes!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Only the speaker can read these notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Press &lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt; key to view&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;themes&#34;&gt;Themes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;black: Black background, white text, blue links (default)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;white: White background, black text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;league: Gray background, white text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;beige: Beige background, dark text, brown links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sky: Blue background, thin dark text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;night: Black background, thick white text, orange links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;serif: Cappuccino background, gray text, brown links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;simple: White background, black text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;solarized: Cream-colored background, dark green text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;section data-noprocess data-shortcode-slide
  
      
      data-background-image=&#34;/media/boards.jpg&#34;
  &gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;custom-slide&#34;&gt;Custom Slide&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Customize the slide style and background&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34; data-lang=&#34;markdown&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;{{&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;slide&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;na&#34;&gt;background-image&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;/media/boards.jpg&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;{{&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;slide&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;na&#34;&gt;background-color&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;#0000FF&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;{{&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;slide&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;na&#34;&gt;class&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;my-style&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;custom-css-example&#34;&gt;Custom CSS Example&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s make headers navy colored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create &lt;code&gt;assets/css/reveal_custom.css&lt;/code&gt; with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-css&#34; data-lang=&#34;css&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nc&#34;&gt;reveal&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;section&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;h1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nc&#34;&gt;reveal&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;section&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;h2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nc&#34;&gt;reveal&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;section&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;h3&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;  &lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;color&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;kc&#34;&gt;navy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;questions&#34;&gt;Questions?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/z8wNYzb&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Ask&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/content/slides/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Datenschutzerklärung</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/privacy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2&gt;Allgemeiner Hinweis und Pflichtinformationen&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Benennung der verantwortlichen Stelle&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Die verantwortliche Stelle für die Datenverarbeitung auf dieser Website ist:&lt;/p&gt;
Andreas Genoni&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;s3-t-strasse&#34;&gt;Friedrich-Ebert-Allee 4&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;s3-t-plz&#34;&gt;65185&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span id=&#34;s3-t-ort&#34;&gt;Wiesbaden&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Die verantwortliche Stelle entscheidet allein oder gemeinsam mit anderen über die Zwecke und Mittel der Verarbeitung von personenbezogenen Daten (z.B. Namen, Kontaktdaten o. Ä.).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Widerruf Ihrer Einwilligung zur Datenverarbeitung&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nur mit Ihrer ausdrücklichen Einwilligung sind einige Vorgänge der Datenverarbeitung möglich. Ein Widerruf Ihrer bereits erteilten Einwilligung ist jederzeit möglich. Für den Widerruf genügt eine formlose Mitteilung per E-Mail. Die Rechtmäßigkeit der bis zum Widerruf erfolgten Datenverarbeitung bleibt vom Widerruf unberührt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Recht auf Beschwerde bei der zuständigen Aufsichtsbehörde&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Als Betroffener steht Ihnen im Falle eines datenschutzrechtlichen Verstoßes ein Beschwerderecht bei der zuständigen Aufsichtsbehörde zu. Zuständige Aufsichtsbehörde bezüglich datenschutzrechtlicher Fragen ist der Landesdatenschutzbeauftragte des Bundeslandes, in dem sich der Sitz unseres Unternehmens befindet. Der folgende Link stellt eine Liste der Datenschutzbeauftragten sowie deren Kontaktdaten bereit: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bfdi.bund.de/DE/Infothek/Anschriften_Links/anschriften_links-node.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://www.bfdi.bund.de/DE/Infothek/Anschriften_Links/anschriften_links-node.html&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Recht auf Datenübertragbarkeit&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ihnen steht das Recht zu, Daten, die wir auf Grundlage Ihrer Einwilligung oder in Erfüllung eines Vertrags automatisiert verarbeiten, an sich oder an Dritte aushändigen zu lassen. Die Bereitstellung erfolgt in einem maschinenlesbaren Format. Sofern Sie die direkte Übertragung der Daten an einen anderen Verantwortlichen verlangen, erfolgt dies nur, soweit es technisch machbar ist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Recht auf Auskunft, Berichtigung, Sperrung, Löschung&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sie haben jederzeit im Rahmen der geltenden gesetzlichen Bestimmungen das Recht auf unentgeltliche Auskunft über Ihre gespeicherten personenbezogenen Daten, Herkunft der Daten, deren Empfänger und den Zweck der Datenverarbeitung und ggf. ein Recht auf Berichtigung, Sperrung oder Löschung dieser Daten. Diesbezüglich und auch zu weiteren Fragen zum Thema personenbezogene Daten können Sie sich jederzeit über die im Impressum aufgeführten Kontaktmöglichkeiten an uns wenden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;SSL- bzw. TLS-Verschlüsselung&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aus Sicherheitsgründen und zum Schutz der Übertragung vertraulicher Inhalte, die Sie an uns als Seitenbetreiber senden, nutzt unsere Website eine SSL-bzw. TLS-Verschlüsselung. Damit sind Daten, die Sie über diese Website übermitteln, für Dritte nicht mitlesbar. Sie erkennen eine verschlüsselte Verbindung an der „https://“ Adresszeile Ihres Browsers und am Schloss-Symbol in der Browserzeile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Server-Log-Dateien&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Server-Log-Dateien erhebt und speichert der Provider der Website automatisch Informationen, die Ihr Browser automatisch an uns übermittelt. Dies sind:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;Besuchte Seite auf unserer Domain&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;Datum und Uhrzeit der Serveranfrage&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;Browsertyp und Browserversion&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;Verwendetes Betriebssystem&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;Referrer URL&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;Hostname des zugreifenden Rechners&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;IP-Adresse&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Es findet keine Zusammenführung dieser Daten mit anderen Datenquellen statt. Grundlage der Datenverarbeitung bildet Art. 6 Abs. 1 lit. b DSGVO, der die Verarbeitung von Daten zur Erfüllung eines Vertrags oder vorvertraglicher Maßnahmen gestattet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Cookies&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unsere Website verwendet Cookies. Das sind kleine Textdateien, die Ihr Webbrowser auf Ihrem Endgerät speichert. Cookies helfen uns dabei, unser Angebot nutzerfreundlicher, effektiver und sicherer zu machen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Einige Cookies sind “Session-Cookies.” Solche Cookies werden nach Ende Ihrer Browser-Sitzung von selbst gelöscht. Hingegen bleiben andere Cookies auf Ihrem Endgerät bestehen, bis Sie diese selbst löschen. Solche Cookies helfen uns, Sie bei Rückkehr auf unserer Website wiederzuerkennen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mit einem modernen Webbrowser können Sie das Setzen von Cookies überwachen, einschränken oder unterbinden. Viele Webbrowser lassen sich so konfigurieren, dass Cookies mit dem Schließen des Programms von selbst gelöscht werden. Die Deaktivierung von Cookies kann eine eingeschränkte Funktionalität unserer Website zur Folge haben.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Das Setzen von Cookies, die zur Ausübung elektronischer Kommunikationsvorgänge oder der Bereitstellung bestimmter, von Ihnen erwünschter Funktionen (z.B. Warenkorb) notwendig sind, erfolgt auf Grundlage von Art. 6 Abs. 1 lit. f DSGVO. Als Betreiber dieser Website haben wir ein berechtigtes Interesse an der Speicherung von Cookies zur technisch fehlerfreien und reibungslosen Bereitstellung unserer Dienste. Sofern die Setzung anderer Cookies (z.B. für Analyse-Funktionen) erfolgt, werden diese in dieser Datenschutzerklärung separat behandelt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Google Analytics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Art und Umfang der Verarbeitung&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wir verwenden Google Analytics von Google Ireland Limited, Gordon House, Barrow Street, Dublin 4, Irland, als Analysedienst zur statistischen Auswertung unseres Onlineangebotes. Diese umfasst beispielsweise die Anzahl der Aufrufe unseres Onlineangebotes, besuchte Unterseiten und die Verweildauer von Besuchern. Google Analytics nutzt Cookies und weitere Browser-Technologien, um Nutzerverhalten auszuwerten und Nutzer wiederzuerkennen. Diese Informationen werden unter anderem genutzt, um Berichte über die Aktivität der Website zusammenzustellen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Zweck und Rechtsgrundlage&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Der Einsatz von Google Analytics erfolgt auf Grundlage Ihrer Einwilligung gemäß Art. 6 Abs. 1 lit. a. DSGVO und § 25 Abs. 1 TTDSG.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wir beabsichtigen personenbezogenen Daten an Drittländer außerhalb des Europäischen Wirtschaftsraums, insbesondere die USA, zu übermitteln. In Fällen, in denen kein Angemessenheitsbeschluss der Europäischen Kommission existiert (z.B. in den USA) haben wir mit den Empfängern der Daten anderweitige geeignete Garantien im Sinne der Art. 44 ff. DSGVO vereinbart. Dies sind – sofern nicht anders angegeben – Standardvertragsklauseln der EU-Kommission gemäß Durchführungsbeschluss (EU) 2021/914 vom 4. Juni 2021. Eine Kopie dieser Standardvertragsklauseln können Sie unter &lt;a href=&#34;https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/DE/TXT/HTML/?uri=CELEX:32021D0914&amp;from=DE&#34;&gt;https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/DE/TXT/HTML/?uri=CELEX:32021D0914&amp;from=DE&lt;/a&gt; einsehen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zudem holen wir vor einem solchen Drittlandtransfer Ihre Einwilligung nach Art. 49 Abs. 1 Satz 1 lit. a. DSGVO ein, die Sie über die Einwilligung im Consent Manager (oder sonstigen Formularen, Registrierungen etc.) erteilen. Wir weisen Sie darauf hin, dass bei Drittlandübermittlungen im Detail unbekannte Risiken (z.B. die Datenverarbeitung durch Sicherheitsbehörden des Drittlandes, deren genauer Umfang und deren Folgen für Sie wir nicht kennen, auf die wir keinen Einfluss haben und von denen Sie unter Umständen keine Kenntnis erlangen) bestehen können.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Speicherdauer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Die konkrete Speicherdauer der verarbeiteten Daten ist nicht durch uns beeinflussbar, sondern wird von Google Ireland Limited bestimmt. Weitere Hinweise finden Sie in der Datenschutzerklärung für Google Analytics: &lt;a href=&#34;https://policies.google.com/privacy&#34;&gt;https://policies.google.com/privacy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Erstellt mithilfe von: Datenschutz-Konfigurator von &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mein-datenschutzbeauftragter.de&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Mein-Datenschutzbeauftragter.de&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/admin/config.yml</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/admin/config.yml</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
