<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Discrimination | Andreas Genoni</title>
    <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/tag/discrimination/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://a-genoni.github.io/tag/discrimination/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Discrimination</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://a-genoni.github.io/media/icon_hu36d72c3cf6f96053b96f9b849fe00da0_28466_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Discrimination</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/tag/discrimination/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ever wondered about the movement of people around the world?</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2023-12-18-global-flow-2.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2023-12-18-global-flow-2.0/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-global-flow-of-people-20&#34;&gt;The Global Flow of People 2.0&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this interactive tool, you can find out which places people around the world leave and which places they move to. You can either look at global migration in general, at global refugees in particular, or at the movement of people within Germany.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The interactive visualisation is part of an international project that I managed and coordinated. &lt;a href=&#34;www.nikolasander.com&#34;&gt;Nikola Sander&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bib.bund.de/DE/Institut/Mitarbeiter/Kolowa/Kolowa.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Tamilwai Kolowa&lt;/a&gt; (both BiB), Tina Frank, Clemens Schrammel (both University of Arts Linz) and Ramon Bauer (Statistics Vienna) were involved.
&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;150&#34; name=&#34;iframe&#34; src=&#34;www.bib.bund.de/DE/Fakten/Tools/Migration/iframe/iframe.html&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
You can find out more about the data and the visualisation on the [main site of our project](www.bib.bund.de/globalflows). There, you will also find more download material such as the underlying data and the R code to create static versions of the circular migration plot.
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New blog post: Unmet expectations of immigrants and their consequences</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2023-11-04-nccr-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2023-11-04-nccr-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Highly qualified immigrants often tend to be under the radar of integration monitors. Due to their  qualifications and integration into local labour markets, we typically tend to assume they are fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, we find that some of them are not. Highly qualified immigrants often have high expectations about life abroad. This makes them particularly vulnerable to disappointment, giving them a hard time to feel welcome, accepted, and to form emotional bonds to their new home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://druedin.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Didier Ruedin&lt;/a&gt; (University of Neuchâtel) and I wrote a short blog post about it, and the potential consequences for both immigrants and host societies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can read the blog post online &lt;a href=&#34;https://nccr-onthemove.ch/blog/departure-for-the-promised-land-unmet-expectations-of-immigrants-and-their-consequences/?lang=de&amp;amp;utm_campaign=shareaholic&amp;amp;utm_medium=twitter&amp;amp;utm_source=socialnetwork&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, or directly download the &lt;a href=&#34;https://a-genoni.github.io/uploads/10_Genoni%20&amp;%20Ruedin.%202023.%20Departure%20for%20the%20Promised%20Land.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;span &gt;PDF&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Expired] Call for Abstracts - IMISCOE Panel on unraveling the Integration Paradox</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2023-09-09-imiscoe-cfp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2023-09-09-imiscoe-cfp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deadline extended until October 11&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next year&amp;rsquo;s IMISCOE conference takes place in sunny Lisbon from July 2 to 5. Together with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ru.nl/en/people/geurts-p&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Nella Geurts&lt;/a&gt; (Radboud University), I&amp;rsquo;m submitting a panel with contributions that aim to unravel the Integration Paradox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you conduct research in this field and have something to contribute? We kindly invite you to submit your &lt;strong&gt;250 words abstract until October 11&lt;/strong&gt; to andreas.genoni(at)bib.bund.de. If you have any questions regarding the panel, don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to contact me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;panel-description&#34;&gt;Panel description&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In many immigration societies, researchers and policymakers still often evaluate the integration status of migrants in terms of more objective indicators such as residence duration, birth place, or education. Thus, when thinking of less and more successful integration, we tend to have specific groups of migrants in mind. However, a considerable number of studies has illustrated that exclusively focusing on more objective indicators of integration is problematic as they do not necessarily match with how migrants perceive their own integration. Opposing classic assimilation theories, various studies have found support for this so-called Integration Paradox where migrants, typically with a higher socio-economic position, feel more socially excluded and less belonging to the residence country. The panel aims to dive into this counterintuitive finding in various ways, for example by examining specific sub-groups, disentangling underlying mechanisms, and exploring new outcomes of interest. We aim to better understand the reasons for why seemingly integrated migrants do not feel like they are, and engage in discussions about individual and societal consequences that arise from this paradox.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The bigger they come, the harder they fall</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2023-08-28-knowledge-societies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2023-08-28-knowledge-societies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The fourth biannual conference of the Academy of Sociology took place at the University of Bern. I presented ongoing collaborative work about &lt;strong&gt;unmet migration expectations and why they are more consequential for higher than for lower educated immigrants&lt;/strong&gt;. Have a look at the presentation slides for first insights into the project. It&amp;rsquo;s an updated version of my talk in Lausanne earlier this year. Email me if you&amp;rsquo;d like to know more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is collaborative work with my colleague &lt;a href=&#34;https://druedin.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Didier Ruedin&lt;/a&gt; from the University of Neuchâtel. We thank all participants for their constructive feedback!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High hopes, high disappointment?</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2023-06-15-shp-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2023-06-15-shp-conference/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;what-happens-when-expectations-of-immigrants-about-live-abroad-do-not-meet-with-their-experiences&#34;&gt;What happens when expectations of immigrants about live abroad do not meet with their experiences?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I gave a talk about how unmet migration expectations influence the lives of immigrants. I started this work together with &lt;a href=&#34;https://druedin.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Didier Ruedin&lt;/a&gt; (University of Neuchâtel) last winter during my research stay at the Swiss National Center of Competence in Research (NCCR) on Migration and Mobility Studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using panel data of the Migration-Mobility Survey (MMS), we observed that unmet migration expectations hit harder on immigrants with tertiary education than immigrants with non-tertiary education. We found robust evidence for comparably stronger perceptions of discrimination (picture) and increased emotional disengagement with Switzerland. Stay tuned for the paper.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unmet migration expectations and their consequences for the lives of immigrants</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/current-work/expectations-and-attachment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/current-work/expectations-and-attachment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Migration research suggests that higher educated migrants report weaker
attachment to their destination country than their lower-educated counterparts.
This so-called integration paradox is probably caused by higher educated migrants
perceiving more discrimination in ambiguous or unfavourable situations. Here we
examine unmet expectations migrants have about their life abroad, experience of
discrimination, and how these account for educational differences in destination
attachment. We use cross-sectional and panel data of recent migrants to Switzerland
from the Swiss Migration-Mobility Survey, capturing unmet expectations with a
question on dissatisfaction with the migration decision. In line with the integration
paradox, we observe lower destination attachment among higher educated migrants
with unmet expectations. Although they more often report discrimination, this
does not explain their lower destination attachment within this group. Instead
of discrimination, adaptation problems matter. Higher educated migrants with unmet
expectations do not outperform their lower-educated counterparts on other integration
dimensions, particularly in social terms. These results indicate that migrants
do not necessarily link unmet expectations to discrimination. Migrants may be
optimistic and particularly vulnerable to disappointment but they can also mitigate
more detrimental consequences, because they are prepared for moving into an unfamiliar
environment despite lacking locally important resources.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
