<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Current-works | Andreas Genoni</title>
    <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/current-work/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://a-genoni.github.io/current-work/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Current-works</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://a-genoni.github.io/media/icon_hu36d72c3cf6f96053b96f9b849fe00da0_28466_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Current-works</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/current-work/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cultural distance and immigrant adjustment</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/current-work/cd-and-adjustment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/current-work/cd-and-adjustment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cultural distance (CD) between the country of origin and destination
country of migrants has long been considered important for adjustment in
international migration. Past research has mainly followed a cost perspective,
pointing to rising costs in adjustment with increasing CD, postulating a negative
linear relationship. Following this logic, previous studies overlooked potential
benefits of CD for adjustment. We address this gap by taking a more differentiated
perspective on CD and adjustment. Using unique probability-based survey data on
German migrants in 38 destination countries with a maximum length of
stay of 36 months, we examined different CD-levels and their consequences for
adjustment. We ran multilevel regressions for sociocultural and psychological
adjustment. Importantly, our findings indicate that the CD effect on adjustment
is not linear but clearly resembles an inverted-U shape for both adjustment
dimensions. This result challenges the cost perspective and suggests an “optimal”
range of intermediate CD as most beneficial for recent migrants’ adjustment. We
conclude that the prevailing view on the consequences of CD for migrant adjustment
holds true for very large CDs, but it underestimates the challenges for culturally
close migrants and overlooks that a certain level of cultural dissimilarity can
facilitate migrants’ adjustment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International migration and subjective well-being</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/current-work/mig-and-swb/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/current-work/mig-and-swb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In many economically highly-developed countries, a relevant proportion
of the population migrates across national boundaries every year. For these
individuals, migrating abroad not only comes with advantages (e.g. monetary
returns) but also with potential pitfalls, because migration is accompanied by
profound changes in everyday life. However, only few and mainly cross-sectional
studies about individuals’ migration expierences exist, analysing the effects
of migration on their quality of life. This study addresses these lacunae and
investigates shifts in subjective well-being (SWB) of internationally mobile
German citizens. We apply fixed effects (FE) panel regression models to data of
the German Emigration and Remigration Panel Study (GERPS). To observe SWB in
the course of migration, we draw on a sample of repeat migrants—Germans who
returned to Germany shortly before the panel and migrated again across international
borders during the panel. As counterfactuals, we focus on Germans who returned
to Germany shortly before the panel but stayed there. Overall life satisfaction
is used as an SWB-indicator, which corresponds to a global assessment of one’s
life situation. In sum, our analyses reveal a happiness dip before migration as
well as an increased and relatively stable SWB at the pre-migration baseline
level in the first two years after migration.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unmet migration expectations and their consequences for the lives of immigrants</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/current-work/expectations-and-attachment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/current-work/expectations-and-attachment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Migration research suggests that higher educated migrants report weaker
attachment to their destination country than their lower-educated counterparts.
This so-called integration paradox is probably caused by higher educated migrants
perceiving more discrimination in ambiguous or unfavourable situations. Here we
examine unmet expectations migrants have about their life abroad, experience of
discrimination, and how these account for educational differences in destination
attachment. We use cross-sectional and panel data of recent migrants to Switzerland
from the Swiss Migration-Mobility Survey, capturing unmet expectations with a
question on dissatisfaction with the migration decision. In line with the integration
paradox, we observe lower destination attachment among higher educated migrants
with unmet expectations. Although they more often report discrimination, this
does not explain their lower destination attachment within this group. Instead
of discrimination, adaptation problems matter. Higher educated migrants with unmet
expectations do not outperform their lower-educated counterparts on other integration
dimensions, particularly in social terms. These results indicate that migrants
do not necessarily link unmet expectations to discrimination. Migrants may be
optimistic and particularly vulnerable to disappointment but they can also mitigate
more detrimental consequences, because they are prepared for moving into an unfamiliar
environment despite lacking locally important resources.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
