<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Call | Andreas Genoni</title>
    <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/category/call/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://a-genoni.github.io/category/call/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Call</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://a-genoni.github.io/media/icon_hu36d72c3cf6f96053b96f9b849fe00da0_28466_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Call</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/category/call/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call for Abstracts for IMISCOE 2026 - Studying the Integration Paradox</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2025-09-03-imiscoe-cfp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2025-09-03-imiscoe-cfp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deadline: 19th of September&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Join our panel at next year&amp;rsquo;s IMISCOE conference in Girona - with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.anthro.ox.ac.uk/people/dr-sanne-van-oosten&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Sanne van Oosten&lt;/a&gt; (Oxford), &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.uu.nl/staff/CLavest&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Chloé Lavest&lt;/a&gt; (Utrecht), &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ru.nl/en/people/geurts-p&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Nella Geurts&lt;/a&gt; (Radboud) and me - to further our efforts in debunking, developing and driving studies on the integration paradox!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🗣️ All are welcome - especially early career researchers are encouraged to apply&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;☀️ We intend to submit both a fully &lt;strong&gt;online&lt;/strong&gt; and a fully &lt;strong&gt;offline&lt;/strong&gt; panel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;✍ What to submit?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Abstract (max. 250 words)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Title&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Authors and affiliations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;📩 Where to submit?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interested in the &lt;strong&gt;online&lt;/strong&gt; panel? Mail your submission to &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:nella.geurts@ru.nl&#34;&gt;nella.geurts@ru.nl&lt;/a&gt;
Interested in the &lt;strong&gt;offline&lt;/strong&gt; panel? Mail your submission to &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:sanne.vanoosten@compas.ox.ac.uk&#34;&gt;sanne.vanoosten@compas.ox.ac.uk&lt;/a&gt;
Please indicate whether joining the other offline/online panel - if need be - is an option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will inform you in the week of September 22.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We look forward to your submissions!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Expired] Call for Abstracts - IMISCOE Panel on unraveling the Integration Paradox</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2023-09-09-imiscoe-cfp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2023-09-09-imiscoe-cfp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deadline extended until October 11&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next year&amp;rsquo;s IMISCOE conference takes place in sunny Lisbon from July 2 to 5. Together with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ru.nl/en/people/geurts-p&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Nella Geurts&lt;/a&gt; (Radboud University), I&amp;rsquo;m submitting a panel with contributions that aim to unravel the Integration Paradox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you conduct research in this field and have something to contribute? We kindly invite you to submit your &lt;strong&gt;250 words abstract until October 11&lt;/strong&gt; to andreas.genoni(at)bib.bund.de. If you have any questions regarding the panel, don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to contact me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;panel-description&#34;&gt;Panel description&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In many immigration societies, researchers and policymakers still often evaluate the integration status of migrants in terms of more objective indicators such as residence duration, birth place, or education. Thus, when thinking of less and more successful integration, we tend to have specific groups of migrants in mind. However, a considerable number of studies has illustrated that exclusively focusing on more objective indicators of integration is problematic as they do not necessarily match with how migrants perceive their own integration. Opposing classic assimilation theories, various studies have found support for this so-called Integration Paradox where migrants, typically with a higher socio-economic position, feel more socially excluded and less belonging to the residence country. The panel aims to dive into this counterintuitive finding in various ways, for example by examining specific sub-groups, disentangling underlying mechanisms, and exploring new outcomes of interest. We aim to better understand the reasons for why seemingly integrated migrants do not feel like they are, and engage in discussions about individual and societal consequences that arise from this paradox.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
