<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Adjustment | Andreas Genoni</title>
    <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/tag/adjustment/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://a-genoni.github.io/tag/adjustment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Adjustment</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://a-genoni.github.io/media/icon_hu36d72c3cf6f96053b96f9b849fe00da0_28466_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Adjustment</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/tag/adjustment/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cultural distance and adaptation</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/project/cultural-contact-in-migration-contexts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/project/cultural-contact-in-migration-contexts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Culture can be considered a relatively stable trait of adult individuals because important parts of personality already form during adolescence. Most individuals emigrate in their adulthood, which means their cultural traits are less malleable once they start living abroad. Cultural differences to non-immigrants therefore become relatively constant distances immigrants have to deal with. Thus, it is important to better understand what role cultural distances play in adapting to a new environment, with increasing time spent abroad, and how immigrants can cope with related challenges. In this project, you will find personal work on these topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;related-work&#34;&gt;Related work&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work in progress | &lt;span style=&#34;color:#93003a&#34;&gt;Cultural distance and immigrant adjustment&lt;/span&gt; | with Jean Philippe Décieux and Elke Murdock | &lt;a href=&#34;https://a-genoni.github.io/current-work/cd-and-adjustment/&#34;&gt;more info&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work in progress | &lt;span style=&#34;color:#93003a&#34;&gt;Expatriate adjustment and the role of cultural distance&lt;/span&gt; | with Jean Philippe Décieux and Heiko Rüger&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cultural distance and immigrant adjustment</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/current-work/cd-and-adjustment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/current-work/cd-and-adjustment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cultural distance (CD) between the country of origin and destination
country of migrants has long been considered important for adjustment in
international migration. Past research has mainly followed a cost perspective,
pointing to rising costs in adjustment with increasing CD, postulating a negative
linear relationship. Following this logic, previous studies overlooked potential
benefits of CD for adjustment. We address this gap by taking a more differentiated
perspective on CD and adjustment. Using unique probability-based survey data on
German migrants in 38 destination countries with a maximum length of
stay of 36 months, we examined different CD-levels and their consequences for
adjustment. We ran multilevel regressions for sociocultural and psychological
adjustment. Importantly, our findings indicate that the CD effect on adjustment
is not linear but clearly resembles an inverted-U shape for both adjustment
dimensions. This result challenges the cost perspective and suggests an “optimal”
range of intermediate CD as most beneficial for recent migrants’ adjustment. We
conclude that the prevailing view on the consequences of CD for migrant adjustment
holds true for very large CDs, but it underestimates the challenges for culturally
close migrants and overlooks that a certain level of cultural dissimilarity can
facilitate migrants’ adjustment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
