<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts | Andreas Genoni</title>
    <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://a-genoni.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Posts</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://a-genoni.github.io/media/icon_hu36d72c3cf6f96053b96f9b849fe00da0_28466_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Posts</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extended Call for Abstracts - IMISCOE Panel on unraveling the Integration Paradox</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2023-09-09-imiscoe-cfp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2023-09-09-imiscoe-cfp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deadline extended until October 11&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next year&amp;rsquo;s IMISCOE conference takes place in sunny Lisbon from July 2 to 5. Together with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ru.nl/en/people/geurts-p&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Nella Geurts&lt;/a&gt; (Radboud University), I&amp;rsquo;m submitting a panel with contributions that aim to unravel the Integration Paradox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you conduct research in this field and have something to contribute? We kindly invite you to submit your &lt;strong&gt;250 words abstract until October 11&lt;/strong&gt; to andreas.genoni(at)bib.bund.de. If you have any questions regarding the panel, don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to contact me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;panel-description&#34;&gt;Panel description&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In many immigration societies, researchers and policymakers still often evaluate the integration status of migrants in terms of more objective indicators such as residence duration, birth place, or education. Thus, when thinking of less and more successful integration, we tend to have specific groups of migrants in mind. However, a considerable number of studies has illustrated that exclusively focusing on more objective indicators of integration is problematic as they do not necessarily match with how migrants perceive their own integration. Opposing classic assimilation theories, various studies have found support for this so-called Integration Paradox where migrants, typically with a higher socio-economic position, feel more socially excluded and less belonging to the residence country. The panel aims to dive into this counterintuitive finding in various ways, for example by examining specific sub-groups, disentangling underlying mechanisms, and exploring new outcomes of interest. We aim to better understand the reasons for why seemingly integrated migrants do not feel like they are, and engage in discussions about individual and societal consequences that arise from this paradox.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The bigger they come, the harder they fall</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2023-08-28-knowledge-societies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2023-08-28-knowledge-societies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The fourth biannual conference of the Academy of Sociology took place at the University of Bern. I presented ongoing collaborative work about &lt;strong&gt;unmet migration expectations and why they are more consequential for higher than for lower educated immigrants&lt;/strong&gt;. Have a look at the presentation slides for first insights into the project. It&amp;rsquo;s an updated version of my talk in Lausanne earlier this year. Email me if you&amp;rsquo;d like to know more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is collaborative work with my colleague &lt;a href=&#34;https://druedin.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Didier Ruedin&lt;/a&gt; from the University of Neuchâtel. We thank all participants for their constructive feedback!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Session on well-being in population research</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2023-07-09-session-on-well-being/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2023-07-09-session-on-well-being/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The session was opened by its chair Katharina Spieß, who introduced the speakers (picture).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bib.bund.de/EN/Institute/Staff/Stawarz/Stawarz.html;jsessionid=CA1C73D7435F153D69470FF104799585.intranet662&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Nico Stawarz&lt;/a&gt; gave a great introductory keynote on why we need to go beyond GDP and other
&amp;ldquo;objective&amp;rdquo; measures of quality of/inequalities in life, and also look on the well-being
of populations. He thereby revealed parts of the progressive research agenda that the BiB will pursue in
the years ahead: Monitoring the well-being of the German population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The highlight were three key notes from &lt;a href=&#34;https://population-europe.eu/network/expert-portraits/mynarska&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Monika Mynarska&lt;/a&gt; (Cardinal Stefan Wyszyński University in Warsaw), &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.martijnhendriks.net/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Martijn Hendriks&lt;/a&gt; (Erasmus University Rotterdam) and &lt;a href=&#34;https://psych.ubc.ca/profile/eric-kim/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Eric Kim&lt;/a&gt; (University of British Columbia), leading scientists in the fields of family, migration, and aging. They provided us with an overview of state-of-the-art research on well-being from their discipline&amp;rsquo;s perspective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks again to all speakers and the organisers! This really was food for thought.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does international migration make people happy?</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2023-07-07-migration-and-swb/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2023-07-07-migration-and-swb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I gave a lightning talk at the BiB&amp;rsquo;s Turning Gold conference about &lt;strong&gt;shifts in subjective well-being in the course of international migration&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;mdash;a study with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bib.bund.de/EN/Institute/Staff/Stawarz/Stawarz.html;jsessionid=CA1C73D7435F153D69470FF104799585.intranet662&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Nico Stawarz&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bib.bund.de/DE/Institut/Mitarbeiter/Ette/Ette.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Andreas Ette&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bib.bund.de/DE/Institut/Mitarbeiter/Rueger/Rueger.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Heiko Rüger&lt;/a&gt; (all BiB).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using unique longitudinal data that includes actual migration events (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gerps-project.de/gerps/EN/Home.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GERPS&lt;/a&gt;), we find robust evidence that the subjective well-being of internationally mobile individuals increases notably with their move abroad (picture).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Round table on dataviz in policy relevant research</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2020-07-06-dataviz-round-table/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2020-07-06-dataviz-round-table/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;what-makes-good-dataviz-for-policy-relevant-research&#34;&gt;What makes good dataviz for policy relevant research?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data visualisation plays an important role in communicating research to others. This is especially the
case in policy-making processes, where researchers want to avoid misinterpretation of empirical evidence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;knowing-our-stuff&#34;&gt;Knowing our stuff&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Participants agreed that for being able to communicate research through visualisations,
researchers first have to understand what they are doing. This may seem like a no-brainer but
researchers have to make themselves familiar with the data they are working with, and,
depending on the discipline, with the mechanisms that contribute to the observed patterns in the data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Researchers are responsible for their products, and responsibility can best be borne by knowledgeable people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;finding-the-middle-ground&#34;&gt;Finding the middle ground&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The challenge that most participants of the round table addressed was to deal
with trade-offs between simplicity and complexity. Policy makers want numbers
to quantify things but a single number often provides incomplete information of complex
relationships in the data. Dataviz helps to attach more information to numbers but
visualising data properly takes more time&amp;mdash;and time is a limited resource in policy-making processes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High hopes, high disappointment?</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2023-06-15-shp-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2023-06-15-shp-conference/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;what-happens-when-expectations-of-immigrants-about-live-abroad-do-not-meet-with-their-experiences&#34;&gt;What happens when expectations of immigrants about live abroad do not meet with their experiences?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I gave a talk about how unmet migration expectations influence the lives of immigrants. I started this work together with &lt;a href=&#34;https://druedin.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Didier Ruedin&lt;/a&gt; (University of Neuchâtel) last winter during my research stay at the Swiss National Center of Competence in Research (NCCR) on Migration and Mobility Studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using panel data of the Migration-Mobility Survey (MMS), we observed that unmet migration expectations hit harder on immigrants with tertiary education than immigrants with non-tertiary education. We found robust evidence for comparably stronger perceptions of discrimination (picture) and increased emotional disengagement with Switzerland. Stay tuned for the paper.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
