<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts | Andreas Genoni</title>
    <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://a-genoni.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Posts</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://a-genoni.github.io/media/icon_hu36d72c3cf6f96053b96f9b849fe00da0_28466_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Posts</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research workshop on unraveling the Integration Paradox</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2025-06-23-workshop-uu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2025-06-23-workshop-uu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After coming back from my research stay in Canberra at the beginning of June, I had to prepare for a research workshop on the Integration Paradox which I co-hosted together with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.uu.nl/staff/CLavest&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Chloé Lavest&lt;/a&gt; (Utrecht University) and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ru.nl/en/people/geurts-p&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Nella Geurts &lt;/a&gt; (Radboud University). The workshop took place in lovely Utrecht, right before the second Migration and Societal Change (MSC) Conference at Utrecht University. This was no coincidence of course. The idea was to join forces and attract as many great people to Utrecht as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Workshop summary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were really unlucky. First, the employees of the dutch railroad company NS went on strike on the day of arrival. While one person from Germany couldn&amp;rsquo;t make it to the workshop because of that, the other international participants struggled quite a bit to get to Utrecht. Then, at the workshop day itself, we realised that protesters have occupied the building in which our workshop should have taken place. Thanks to Chloé, a last-minute room change was possible. Now, we only had to direct everyone to the new place shortly before the event kicked-off, re-order catering and set up the IT at the new venue. Sounds stressful? Well, at least I can say that we were no longer stressed about conducting the workshop itself&amp;ndash;which was a huge success against all odds!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had the pleasure to listen to nine interesting presentations that dived into the mechanisms underlying the Integration Paradox. Among others, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.soziologie.uni-konstanz.de/diehl/team/prof-dr-claudia-diehl/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Claudia Diehl&lt;/a&gt; (University of Konstanz) talked about perceived wage unfairness, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.compas.ox.ac.uk/people/sanne-van-oosten&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Sanne van Oosten&lt;/a&gt; (Oxford University) about reasons for heightened discrimination awareness among highly educated immigrants, and Ben van Enk about the Integration Paradox from a country-level perspective, focusing on EU countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I presented ongoing work with &lt;a href=&#34;https://druedin.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Didier Ruedin&lt;/a&gt; (University of Neuchâtel), in which we show that the Integration Paradox isn’t just about highly educated immigrants. Less-educated immigrants also play a role. And depending on how recognisable someone is as an immigrant, the paradox tends to emerge at different stages of their stay in the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conference summary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the MSC Conference, we organised a roundtable on the Integration Paradox to communicate our insights from the workshop to a wider audience, discuss the current state of research and future avenues within our field. Nella, Chloé, Claudia and I were interested to engage with the audience to hear their opinion on the status quo and promising further research. We were surprised how many people attended our roundtable and actively participated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What was the bottom line? The unraveling of the Integration Paradox is ongoing! As a consequence, the field is united by this one term, which at the same time is becoming increasingly obsolete due to the progress in research. Who knows, maybe we need to find a new title for a potential next workshop&amp;hellip; ;-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A big shout out to everyone who was there! Without you, this event wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have made much sense.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research stay at the Australian National University (ANU)</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2025-05-06-stay-at-anu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2025-05-06-stay-at-anu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Have you ever heard of Canberra? It is the planned capital city of Australia, which was built in the early 20th century. It is also the place where you can find the Australian National University (ANU), where I visited the School of Demography at the ANU College of Arts &amp;amp; Social Sciences in May 2025.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My colleague &lt;a href=&#34;https://researchportalplus.anu.edu.au/en/persons/natalie-nitsche&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Natalie Nitsche&lt;/a&gt; works at ANU. She is a demographer and sociologist with whom I&amp;rsquo;m collaborating in a project on the impact of first-time parenthood on immigrants&amp;rsquo; socio-emotional life at the intersection of gender and education. We had the opportunity to present our paper at the regular colloquium and received great feedback that helped us further developing the project during my stay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned for more input later this year.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inaugural conference of the Population Research Center (PRC) at Uni Zurich</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2025-01-25-prc-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2025-01-25-prc-conference/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The recently founded Population Research Center (PRC) at the University of Zurich organised an inaugural conference, inviting population scientists across disciplines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These were an inspiring two days. I&amp;rsquo;m always surprised by the constructive feedback, lively discussions and exchange at interdisciplinary conferences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took the chance to talk about an ongoing research project of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.unige.ch/sciences-societe/ideso/membres/wanner/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Philippe Wanner&lt;/a&gt; (Université de Genève), &lt;a href=&#34;https://druedin.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Didier Ruedin&lt;/a&gt; (Université de Neuchâtel) and myself, in which we investigate whether unmet migration expectations increase the chance that immigrants leave the country to which they have just immigrated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We created an original panel data set by linking Swiss survey data with Swiss admin data. This way, we connected individual-level information of immigrants with registry information on their whereabouts after they have dropped out of the survey. This project takes a behavioural perspective on the integration paradox and investigates whether disappointment about life abroad not only weaken immigrants&amp;rsquo; emotional bonds to their destination country but also actually make them leave. Your hunch? Have a look at the findings &lt;a href=&#34;https://a-genoni.github.io/current-work/outmigration/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I already presented this project at last year&amp;rsquo;s ECSR in Barcelona. However, I took the time in-between the conferences to update the manuscript and the talk. I would like to thank all participants for great feedback. Can&amp;rsquo;t wait until the first full draft of the paper.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call for abstracts: Workshop on the integration paradox</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2024-11-20-cfp-ip-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2024-11-20-cfp-ip-workshop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;do-you-study-the-integration-paradox-ip&#34;&gt;Do you study the integration paradox (IP)?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If so, I kindly invite you to apply to participate in an international research workshop on the topic, which I co-organise in June &amp;lsquo;25 with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ru.nl/en/people/geurts-p&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Nella Geurts&lt;/a&gt; (Radboud University) and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.uu.nl/staff/CLavest&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Chloé Lavest&lt;/a&gt; (Utrecht University).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The integration paradox describes the phenomenon that seemingly well-integrated immigrants and their descendants often experience more discrimination and weaker belongingness to their new place of residence than their not-so-well-integrated counterparts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The IP literature has expanded significantly in recent years, but it still falls short on longitudinal perspectives and empirical evidence on the underlying mechanisms and scope of countries and migrant groups studied. We thus call for papers to further advance IP research and connect with other colleagues in the field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The workshop will take place &lt;strong&gt;at Utrecht University on June 18, 2025&lt;/strong&gt;, just before the Migration and Societal Change conference. We plan to produce a Special Issue based on the contributions presented during the workshop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more details, have a look at &lt;a href=&#34;https://a-genoni.github.io/uploads/CfP-workshop.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;span &gt;this information sheet&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-deadline-for-applications-is-february-1-2025&#34;&gt;The deadline for applications is February 1, 2025.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We look forward to receiving your submissions!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New publication: A practical guide for creating circular migration plots</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2024-10-19-publication-dataviz/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2024-10-19-publication-dataviz/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are you starting a project on the migration of people? Do you need some practical advice and guidance about how to visualise these people&amp;rsquo;s movement? If so, this hands-on article might come in handy for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-the-article-could-be-valuable-for-you&#34;&gt;Why the article could be valuable for you&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visualising migration flows can be a messy endeavour. Using world maps as a basis has proven impractical due to the different sizes of countries or regions and migration flows that go in and out from designated areas. Dataviz techniques such as flow charts perform a bit better with respect to variation in size of regions and flows, but struggle as soon as there are too many regions that you want to visualise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With circular migration plots (simplified version in the image above), you are able to visualise migration inflows and outflows between numerous regions at the same time without overburdening your readers. In the article, we give you practical advice on how to create your own plots and provide free access to the necessary R code (see also below). We discuss the pros and cons of visualising migration flows using circular migration plots, and talk about colour choice, accessibility and other design elements creators have to decide upon, giving examples of better and less good implementations of such decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;get-the-article-and-code-for-free&#34;&gt;Get the article and code for free&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You find the article online at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.elgaronline.com/edcollchap/book/9781800378032/book-part-9781800378032-32.xml&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Edward Elgar Publishing&lt;/a&gt;. Just get in touch with me if you lack access. The code and data to reproduce the plots we created in the article are available for free on my &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/a-genoni/visualising-migration-data&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Github repository&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;credits&#34;&gt;Credits&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This contribution is joint-work with my dear and former colleague &lt;a href=&#34;http://nikolasander.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Nikola Sander&lt;/a&gt;. She was instrumental in establishing the circular plot in migration research. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1126/science.1248676&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt; you can check out her seminal paper about &amp;ldquo;quantifying global international migration flows&amp;rdquo;, which was published in &lt;em&gt;Science&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;interactive-visualisation-of-migration-flows&#34;&gt;Interactive visualisation of migration flows&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also created an interactive tool with which you can browse through the past 30 years of global international migration and refugee flows, and internal migration flows in Germany. The tool is very useful to learn about the history and changes of the movement of people worldwide. You can download all the materials, including static visualizations of the tool, a poster of the project, and code to reproduce the tool and the static plots &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bib.bund.de/EN/Service/Tools/Migration/Globalflows.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. This project was realised together with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bib.bund.de/DE/Institut/Mitarbeiter/Kolowa/Kolowa.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Tamilwai Kolowa (BiB)&lt;/a&gt;, Tina Frank, Clemens Schrammel (both University of Arts Linz), and Ramon Bauer (Statistics Vienna).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The conference summer goes on</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2024-09-22-sgs-and-ecsr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2024-09-22-sgs-and-ecsr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, almost everybody in the office had his/her conference trip this year. Thus, it was about time to head out myself to meet new people, chat with dear colleagues, and talk about ongoing projects to get some feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ssa-an-early-integration-paradox&#34;&gt;SSA: An early integration paradox?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first stop was Muttenz, a place close to Basel, where this years congress of the Swiss Sociological Association (SSA) took place. I had the opportunity to present an ongoing research project of &lt;a href=&#34;https://druedin.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Didier Ruedin&lt;/a&gt; (Université de Neuchâtel) and myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project uses longitudinal data of immigrants who recently arrived in Switzerland to explore the possibility of an &amp;ldquo;early&amp;rdquo; integration paradox as we refer to it. Scholars typically argue that the integration paradox, the phenomenon that seemingly integrated immigrants do not perceive themselves as integrated, actually reflects progress in integration. The reasoning behind this argument is that if immigrants and locals become more similar, the smaller differences become more salient and potentially problematic&amp;ndash;particularly for immigrants with visually distinct phenotypical markers or clothing. Clearly, this argument neglects the situation of recent immigrants who are at the beginning of their integration process. In our study, we investigate whether immigrants in this early stage might experience an integration paradox as well, and discuss why visually distinct immigrants of all people might be less affected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ecsr-should-i-stay-or-should-i-go-out-migration-of-recent-immigrants-to-switzerland&#34;&gt;ECSR: Should I stay or should I go? Out-migration of recent immigrants to Switzerland&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second stop was Barcelona, the capitol of Catalonia. The European Consortium for Sociological Research (ECSR) held its annual conference at the Universitat Pompeu Fabra. Besides getting inspired by great people and their projects, I had the honour to present a project of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.unige.ch/sciences-societe/ideso/membres/wanner/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Philippe Wanner&lt;/a&gt; (Université de Genève), &lt;a href=&#34;https://druedin.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Didier Ruedin&lt;/a&gt; (Université de Neuchâtel) and myself, in which we investigate whether unmet migration expectations increase the chance that immigrants leave the country to which they have just immigrated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We created an original panel data set by linking Swiss survey data with Swiss admin data. This way, we connected individual-level information of immigrants with registry information on their whereabouts after they have dropped out of the survey. This project takes a behavioural perspective on the integration paradox and investigates whether disappointment about life abroad not only weaken immigrants&amp;rsquo; emotional bonds to their destination country but also actually make them leave. Your hunch? Have a look at the findings &lt;a href=&#34;https://a-genoni.github.io/current-work/outmigration/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New research at the 16th ESA conference</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2024-08-27-esa-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2024-08-27-esa-conference/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While I took advantage of everyone being OUT of office to be productive IN the office, my dear colleagues Lenore and Nico presented ongoing mutual work in sunny Porto at the 16th ESA conference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;an-integration-paradox-among-the-most-religious-migrants&#34;&gt;An integration paradox among the most religious migrants?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The joint study with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bib.bund.de/DE/Institut/Mitarbeiter/Sauer/Sauer.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Lenore Sauer&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bib.bund.de/DE/Institut/Mitarbeiter/Milewski/Milewski.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Nadja Milewski&lt;/a&gt; investigates the relationship between migrants&amp;rsquo; level of education, degree of religiosity, and feelings of belongingness. We use data from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bib.bund.de/P/Transfar/EN/About/Transfar.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;TransFAR project&lt;/a&gt;, a BiB survey about Eritrean and Syrian recent refugees in Germany. In essence, our study examines whether the degree of religiosity is an explaining factor for the so-called integration paradox, the phenomenon that highly educated migrants do not really feel as integrated as one would expect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;return-of-the-failed-the-subjective-well-being-of-german-returnees&#34;&gt;Return of the failed? The subjective well-being of German returnees&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bib.bund.de/DE/Institut/Mitarbeiter/Stawarz/Stawarz.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Nico Stawarz&lt;/a&gt; presented the second study, in which we investigate shifts in the subjective well-being of German migrants in the course of their return to Germany. By looking at well-being trajectories of Germans with different return motives, we put contradicting theories about reasons for return migration to the test. Are returnees really those who lost the game of migration and travel back defeated, or could they be those who have successfully completed their stay abroad? This is collaborative work with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.martijnhendriks.net/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Martijn Hendriks&lt;/a&gt; (Erasmus University Rotterdam).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New publication about the well-being of international migrants</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2024-03-20-publication-swb/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2024-03-20-publication-swb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Moving abroad can both be a challenging but also rewarding event in people&amp;rsquo;s lives. Internationally mobile people often leave relevant others and material belongings behind and often find themselves in an unfamiliar environment, within which they sometimes even face reservations from the local population. As if all of this is not enough, moving abroad needs careful planning ahead, ensuring that crossing national borders and changing one&amp;rsquo;s place of residence is in accordance with all involved countries&amp;rsquo; laws. Sounds quite stressful!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With so much stuff going on in the process of emigration, it&amp;rsquo;s hard to keep track of how well international migrants are doing overall. Clearly, just looking at how their income changes with the move doesn&amp;rsquo;t do justice to everything that is going on. We thus took a different approach an looked at shifts in the subjective well-being of individuals that are in the process of leaving their country to life somewhere else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This study is unique as it is one of the first that is following people throughout their whole emigration process. This is made possible with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://gerps-project.de/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;German Emigration and Remigration Panel Study (GERPS)&lt;/a&gt;, a longitudinal study that is representative of the internationally mobile German population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-results-in-a-nutshell&#34;&gt;The results in a nutshell&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are able to show a general increase in people&amp;rsquo;s well-being during their emigration. Importantly, this increase is not short-term as well-being remains elevated in the first years after migration. The extent of the change in well-being thereby systematically depends on negotiation processes related to the migration decision: accompanying individuals (so-called trailing partners) experience the smallest gains in well-being compared to those who made the migration decision jointly with their partner or those who were the driving force behind the migration (so-called leading partners). Being unconstrained by a partner, singles even showed more pronounced increases in their well-being.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-can-we-learn-from-the-study&#34;&gt;What can we learn from the study?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The study suggests that, despite its associated challenges, international migration is generally positive for people from affluent societies. The increasing internationalization of education and careers, along with subsequent high return rates, supports policies that promote international mobility as recurring events in people&amp;rsquo;s lives. However, the findings also highlight potential social inequalities between those who migrate internationally and those who don&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;get-the-article&#34;&gt;Get the article&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in reading the whole article, you can head over to &lt;a href=&#34;https://academic.oup.com/migration/advance-article-abstract/doi/10.1093/migration/mnae008/7630980?redirectedFrom=fulltext#supplementary-data&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Migration Studies&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to get in touch with me if you lack access.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;credits&#34;&gt;Credits&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article is collaborative work with my dear colleagues &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bib.bund.de/DE/Institut/Mitarbeiter/Stawarz/Stawarz.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Nico Stawarz&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bib.bund.de/DE/Institut/Mitarbeiter/Ette/Ette.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Andreas Ette&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bib.bund.de/DE/Institut/Mitarbeiter/Rueger/Rueger.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Heiko Rüger&lt;/a&gt; from the Federal Institute for Population Research (BiB).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is &#34;Reactive Cosmopolitanism&#34; a thing?</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2024-03-19-nella-in-wiesbaden/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2024-03-19-nella-in-wiesbaden/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the most exciting and enriching things in my profession is the chance to get to know great and like-minded people from all around the world, exchange ideas with them, learn from them, laugh with them and collaborate with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week, my dear colleague and friend &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ru.nl/en/people/geurts-p&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Nella Geurts&lt;/a&gt; (Radboud University, NL) visited me at the BiB in Wiesbaden to work on a mutual project based on our &lt;a href=&#34;https://gerps-project.de/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GERPS data&lt;/a&gt;. We had the chance to present our work in process in front of my BiB fellows and to get valuable feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You wonder what the project is about? Well, we do not want to already spoil too much at this point but you can already find an abstract &lt;a href=&#34;https://a-genoni.github.io/current-work/reactive-cosmopolitanism/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ever wondered about the movement of people around the world?</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2023-12-18-global-flow-2.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2023-12-18-global-flow-2.0/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-global-flow-of-people-20&#34;&gt;The Global Flow of People 2.0&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this interactive tool, you can find out which places people around the world leave and which places they move to. You can either look at global migration in general, at global refugees in particular, or at the movement of people within Germany.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The interactive visualisation is part of an international project that I managed and coordinated. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bib.bund.de/DE/Institut/Mitarbeiter/Sander/Sander.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Nikola Sander&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bib.bund.de/DE/Institut/Mitarbeiter/Kolowa/Kolowa.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Tamilwai Kolowa&lt;/a&gt; (both BiB), Tina Frank, Clemens Schrammel (both University of Arts Linz) and Ramon Bauer (Statistics Vienna) were involved.
&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;1100&#34; name=&#34;iframe&#34; src=&#34;https://www.bib.bund.de/EN/Service/Tools/Migration/iframe/iframe.html&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
You can find out more about the data and the visualisation on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bib.bund.de/EN/Service/Tools/Migration/Globalflows.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;main site of our project&lt;/a&gt;. There, you will also find more download material such as the underlying data and R scripts to create static versions of the interactive circular migration plot.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New blog post: Unmet expectations of immigrants and their consequences</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2023-11-04-nccr-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2023-11-04-nccr-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Highly qualified immigrants often tend to be under the radar of integration monitors. Due to their  qualifications and integration into local labour markets, we typically tend to assume they are fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, we find that some of them are not. Highly qualified immigrants often have high expectations about life abroad. This makes them particularly vulnerable to disappointment, giving them a hard time to feel welcome, accepted, and to form emotional bonds to their new home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://druedin.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Didier Ruedin&lt;/a&gt; (University of Neuchâtel) and I wrote a short blog post about it, and the potential consequences for both immigrants and host societies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can read the blog post online &lt;a href=&#34;https://nccr-onthemove.ch/blog/departure-for-the-promised-land-unmet-expectations-of-immigrants-and-their-consequences/?lang=de&amp;amp;utm_campaign=shareaholic&amp;amp;utm_medium=twitter&amp;amp;utm_source=socialnetwork&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, or directly download the &lt;a href=&#34;https://a-genoni.github.io/uploads/10_Genoni%20&amp;%20Ruedin.%202023.%20Departure%20for%20the%20Promised%20Land.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;span &gt;PDF&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The BiB Well-Being Monitor 2023</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2023-10-05-wb-monitor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2023-10-05-wb-monitor/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The BiB has a new flagship product: The BiB Well-Being Monitor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Its idea is to inform the public and policy makers about the well-being of the German population. Among existing transfer publications on well-being, the monitor stands out with its focus on the most dissatisfied and satisfied people in the population. Going beyond the average well-being level of groups makes the report particularly useful for policy makers to maintain the well-being of the highly satisfied and improve the well-being of the most vulnerable groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The monitor is written in German but I give you a quick summary about what we&amp;rsquo;ve found for the migrant population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;children-of-immigrants-are-the-least-satisfied&#34;&gt;Children of immigrants are the least satisfied&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compared to immigrants and the resident population, children of immigrants are the least satisfied. They more often report particularly low satisfaction with their life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take a look at the figure above: The children of immigrants&amp;ndash;or the people from the so-called second generation&amp;ndash;are shown in the middle. They have the highest share of people who are less satisfied (39.7%, represented by the blueish bar), and the lowest share of people who are very satisfied (12.1%, represented by the greenish bar).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These shares particularly contrast those in the immigrant population&amp;ndash;the so-called first generation&amp;ndash;, which you see on the far right in the figure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;smaller-differences-bigger-impact&#34;&gt;Smaller differences, bigger impact&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Strange, isn&amp;rsquo;t it? The second generation, whose living conditions are more similar to those of the resident population, are less satisfied than the first generation who immigrated themselves and have to find their way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most plausible explanations for this difference is that first- and second-generation migrants tend to use different reference points against which they evaluate their life and satisfaction with it. While immigrants more likely compare their current life abroad to their past in the origin country or non-migrated peers, children of immigrants tend to compare their situation more likely to that of the resident population. For immigrants, the comparison often feels positive, knowing that they left for a (hopefully) better future. For their children however, the comparison is often to their disadvantage, revealing the admittedly smaller but still existing inequalities that clash with unmet desires of same life chances and equal treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;more-information&#34;&gt;More information&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can download the Monitor &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bib.bund.de/Publikation/2023/BiB-Monitor-2023-Wohlbefinden-Wie-zufrieden-ist-die-Bevoelkerung-in-Deutschland.html?nn=1219342&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. (German only)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.freda-panel.de/FReDA/EN/Startseite.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, you find more information on the FReDA Panel, the data on which the Monitor is based. (English and German)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Expired] Call for Abstracts - IMISCOE Panel on unraveling the Integration Paradox</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2023-09-09-imiscoe-cfp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2023-09-09-imiscoe-cfp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deadline extended until October 11&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next year&amp;rsquo;s IMISCOE conference takes place in sunny Lisbon from July 2 to 5. Together with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ru.nl/en/people/geurts-p&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Nella Geurts&lt;/a&gt; (Radboud University), I&amp;rsquo;m submitting a panel with contributions that aim to unravel the Integration Paradox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you conduct research in this field and have something to contribute? We kindly invite you to submit your &lt;strong&gt;250 words abstract until October 11&lt;/strong&gt; to andreas.genoni(at)bib.bund.de. If you have any questions regarding the panel, don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to contact me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;panel-description&#34;&gt;Panel description&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In many immigration societies, researchers and policymakers still often evaluate the integration status of migrants in terms of more objective indicators such as residence duration, birth place, or education. Thus, when thinking of less and more successful integration, we tend to have specific groups of migrants in mind. However, a considerable number of studies has illustrated that exclusively focusing on more objective indicators of integration is problematic as they do not necessarily match with how migrants perceive their own integration. Opposing classic assimilation theories, various studies have found support for this so-called Integration Paradox where migrants, typically with a higher socio-economic position, feel more socially excluded and less belonging to the residence country. The panel aims to dive into this counterintuitive finding in various ways, for example by examining specific sub-groups, disentangling underlying mechanisms, and exploring new outcomes of interest. We aim to better understand the reasons for why seemingly integrated migrants do not feel like they are, and engage in discussions about individual and societal consequences that arise from this paradox.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The bigger they come, the harder they fall</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2023-08-28-knowledge-societies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2023-08-28-knowledge-societies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The fourth biannual conference of the Academy of Sociology took place at the University of Bern. I presented ongoing collaborative work about &lt;strong&gt;unmet migration expectations and why they are more consequential for higher than for lower educated immigrants&lt;/strong&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s an updated talk from that in Lausanne earlier this year. Email me if you&amp;rsquo;d like to know more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is collaborative work with my colleague &lt;a href=&#34;https://druedin.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Didier Ruedin&lt;/a&gt; from the University of Neuchâtel. We thank all participants for their constructive feedback!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Session on well-being in population research</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2023-07-09-session-on-well-being/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2023-07-09-session-on-well-being/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The session was opened by its chair Katharina Spieß, who introduced the speakers (picture).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bib.bund.de/EN/Institute/Staff/Stawarz/Stawarz.html;jsessionid=CA1C73D7435F153D69470FF104799585.intranet662&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Nico Stawarz&lt;/a&gt; gave a great introductory keynote on why we need to go beyond GDP and other
&amp;ldquo;objective&amp;rdquo; measures of quality of/inequalities in life, and also look on the well-being
of populations. He thereby revealed parts of the progressive research agenda that the BiB will pursue in
the years ahead: Monitoring the well-being of the German population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The highlight were three key notes from &lt;a href=&#34;https://population-europe.eu/network/expert-portraits/mynarska&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Monika Mynarska&lt;/a&gt; (Cardinal Stefan Wyszyński University in Warsaw), &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.martijnhendriks.net/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Martijn Hendriks&lt;/a&gt; (Erasmus University Rotterdam) and &lt;a href=&#34;https://psych.ubc.ca/profile/eric-kim/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Eric Kim&lt;/a&gt; (University of British Columbia), leading scientists in the fields of family, migration, and aging. They provided us with an overview of state-of-the-art research on well-being from their discipline&amp;rsquo;s perspective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks again to all speakers and the organisers! This really was food for thought.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does international migration make people happy?</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2023-07-07-migration-and-swb/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2023-07-07-migration-and-swb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I gave a lightning talk at the BiB&amp;rsquo;s Turning Gold conference about &lt;strong&gt;shifts in subjective well-being in the course of international migration&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;mdash;a study with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bib.bund.de/EN/Institute/Staff/Stawarz/Stawarz.html;jsessionid=CA1C73D7435F153D69470FF104799585.intranet662&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Nico Stawarz&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bib.bund.de/DE/Institut/Mitarbeiter/Ette/Ette.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Andreas Ette&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bib.bund.de/DE/Institut/Mitarbeiter/Rueger/Rueger.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Heiko Rüger&lt;/a&gt; (all BiB).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using unique longitudinal data that includes actual migration events (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gerps-project.de/gerps/EN/Home.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GERPS&lt;/a&gt;), we find robust evidence that the subjective well-being of internationally mobile individuals increases notably with their move abroad (picture).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Round table on dataviz in policy relevant research</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2020-07-06-dataviz-round-table/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2020-07-06-dataviz-round-table/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;what-makes-good-dataviz-for-policy-relevant-research&#34;&gt;What makes good dataviz for policy relevant research?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data visualisation plays an important role in communicating research to others. This is especially the
case in policy-making processes, where researchers want to avoid misinterpretation of empirical evidence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;knowing-our-stuff&#34;&gt;Knowing our stuff&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Participants agreed that for being able to communicate research through visualisations,
researchers first have to understand what they are doing. This may seem like a no-brainer but
researchers have to make themselves familiar with the data they are working with, and,
depending on the discipline, with the mechanisms that contribute to the observed patterns in the data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Researchers are responsible for their products, and responsibility can best be borne by knowledgeable people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;finding-the-middle-ground&#34;&gt;Finding the middle ground&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The challenge that most participants of the round table addressed was to deal
with trade-offs between simplicity and complexity. Policy makers want numbers
to quantify things but a single number often provides incomplete information of complex
relationships in the data. Dataviz helps to attach more information to numbers but
visualising data properly takes more time&amp;mdash;and time is a limited resource in policy-making processes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High hopes, high disappointment?</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2023-06-15-shp-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2023-06-15-shp-conference/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;what-happens-when-expectations-of-immigrants-about-live-abroad-do-not-meet-with-their-experiences&#34;&gt;What happens when expectations of immigrants about live abroad do not meet with their experiences?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I gave a talk about how unmet migration expectations influence the lives of immigrants. I started this work together with &lt;a href=&#34;https://druedin.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Didier Ruedin&lt;/a&gt; (University of Neuchâtel) last winter during my research stay at the Swiss National Center of Competence in Research (NCCR) on Migration and Mobility Studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using panel data of the Migration-Mobility Survey (MMS), we observed that unmet migration expectations hit harder on immigrants with tertiary education than immigrants with non-tertiary education. We found robust evidence for comparably stronger perceptions of discrimination (picture) and increased emotional disengagement with Switzerland. Stay tuned for the paper.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
