<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | Andreas Genoni</title>
    <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://a-genoni.github.io/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://a-genoni.github.io/media/icon_hu36d72c3cf6f96053b96f9b849fe00da0_28466_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysing and visualising human migration</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/project/human-migration/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/project/human-migration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This project features personal work on human migration and mobility from a macro perspective. I study  patterns and trends in various forms of spatial mobility in order to reveal interdependencies between them, and to better understand population dynamics. For this purpose, parts of my work are explicitly dedicated to the visualisation of human migration flows by using circular migration plots. Circular migration plots are a viable alternative to conventional flow maps and other existing visualisations of migration flows. They are an effective and visually appealing method for visualising flow data because they allow the reader to quickly identify key patterns and trends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will find guidance and code that help you create your own circular migration plots in the context of &amp;ldquo;The Global Flow of People 2.0&amp;rdquo; project and the handbook article listed below. Don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to contact me if you have any further questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;related-work&#34;&gt;Related work&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2023 | &lt;span style=&#34;color:#93003a&#34;&gt;Who moves where? Global Migration Flows between 2015-2020&lt;/span&gt; &amp;mdash; A poster of international migration flows between the top-50 countries with the largest volume of migration | with Nikola Sander, Tamilwai Kolowa, Tina Frank, and Clemens Schrammel | &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/KunstuniLinzViskom&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PDF (available in English and German)&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2021 | &lt;span style=&#34;color:#93003a&#34;&gt;Globale Bevölkerungsentwicklung. Fakten und Trends.&lt;/span&gt; BiB.Bevölkerungs.Studien 1/2021. Wiesbaden: BiB | &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bib.bund.de/Publikation/2021/Globale-Bevoelkerungsentwicklung.html?nn=1219558&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Forthcoming | &lt;span style=&#34;color:#93003a&#34;&gt;The Global Flow of People 2.0.&lt;/span&gt; &amp;mdash; An interactive application that visualises global human migration over the past 30 years | with Nikola Sander, Tamilwai Kolowa, Tina Frank, and Clemens Schrammel
&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Forthcoming | &lt;span style=&#34;color:#93003a&#34;&gt;Data visualisation in migration research. The case of circular migration plots.&lt;/span&gt; In Vargas-Silva, C. &amp;amp; Allen, W. (Eds.). &lt;em&gt;Handbook of Research Methods in Migration. Second edition.&lt;/em&gt; Edward Elgar Publishing | with Nikola Sander
&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work in progress | &lt;span style=&#34;color:#93003a&#34;&gt;How have commuting, internal and international migration  changed over time? A trend study of three mobilities using German Microcensus data&lt;/span&gt; | with Nico Stawarz, Heiko Rüger, Andreas Ette, Thomas Skora, Matthias Rosenbaum-Feldbrügge, and Nikola Sander&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cultural distance and adaptation</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/project/cultural-contact-in-migration-contexts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/project/cultural-contact-in-migration-contexts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Culture can be considered a relatively stable trait of adult individuals because important parts of personality already form during adolescence. Most individuals emigrate in their adulthood, which means their cultural traits are less malleable once they start living abroad. Cultural differences to non-immigrants therefore become relatively constant distances immigrants have to deal with. Thus, it is important to better understand what role cultural distances play in adapting to a new environment, with increasing time spent abroad, and how immigrants can cope with related challenges. In this project, you will find personal work on these topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;related-work&#34;&gt;Related work&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work in progress | &lt;span style=&#34;color:#93003a&#34;&gt;Cultural distance and adjustment of recent immigrants&lt;/span&gt; | with Jean Philippe Décieux and Elke Murdock | &lt;a href=&#34;https://a-genoni.github.io/uploads/Genoni%20et%20al.%20Cultural%20distance%20and%20adjustment.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;span &gt;Slides&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  | &lt;a href=&#34;https://a-genoni.github.io/current-work/cd-and-adjustment/&#34;&gt;Scientific abstract&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work in progress | &lt;span style=&#34;color:#93003a&#34;&gt;Expatriate adjustment and the role of cultural distance&lt;/span&gt; | with Jean Philippe Décieux and Heiko Rüger&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The paradox of integration</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/project/paradox-of-integration/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/project/paradox-of-integration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Research and regular monitors about the integration of immigrants has typically looked at &amp;ldquo;objective&amp;rdquo; indicators of integration such as education, stable employment, language skills or income. In the past years, however, increasingly more attention has been given to the &amp;ldquo;inner life&amp;rdquo; of immigrants, referring to more &amp;ldquo;subjective&amp;rdquo; indicators of integration such as their emotional attachment to the new home, their feelings of belongingness to its society or their perceptions of discrimination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the continued publication of empirical studies on immigrants&amp;rsquo; subjective integration, an integration paradox has been revealed: Many of those immigrants who seem integrated in terms of their education or occupational status do not feel that they are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such a misalignment can be problematic because it may increase the likelihood of frustration, mental health issues, and emigration. But the seemingly better integrated are particularly valuable for receiving societies because they can play an important role in helping new arrivals to participate and incorporate into the institutions of the mainstream society. Furthermore, they are more efficiently deployable in the local labour market and less at risk from unemployment. These issues are particularly pressing in times when many developed countries face labour shortages and compete for talents globally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project bundles personal work on the integration paradox. It looks at different factors and mechanisms that contribute to this paradox, and tries to better understand the potential issues and consequences related to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;related-work&#34;&gt;Related work&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2022 | &lt;span style=&#34;color:#93003a&#34;&gt;Status and Ethnic Identity. A Study on First- and Second-Generation Migrants in Germany.&lt;/span&gt; Verlag Barbara Budrich | &lt;a href=&#34;https://a-genoni.github.io/publication/genoni-2022-status-and-ethnic-identity/&#34;&gt;Publication&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work in progress | &lt;span style=&#34;color:#93003a&#34;&gt;Unmet migration expectations and their consequences for the lives of immigrants&lt;/span&gt; | with Didier Ruedin | &lt;a href=&#34;https://a-genoni.github.io/current-work/expectations-and-attachment/&#34;&gt;Scientific abstract&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;https://a-genoni.github.io/uploads/10_Genoni%20&amp;%20Ruedin.%202023.%20Departure%20for%20the%20Promised%20Land.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;span &gt;Blog post&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The well-being of immigrants: The role of migration, past and present life</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/project/well-being/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/project/well-being/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Who doesn&amp;rsquo;t know them, the fairy tales of Brother&amp;rsquo;s Grimm? Although there are many, the fantastic stories from our childhood have one thing in common: their promise, that no matter what hard times a protagonist goes through, his or her efforts will eventually be rewarded with eternal happiness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much like the heroes and heroines of these timeless tales, today, millions of people around the world  embark on their own arduous journeys, voluntarily or involuntarily, and leave behind their homeland in search of a brighter future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project brings together work about whether these people succeed, and the factors that contribute to achieving or missing their goal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;related-work&#34;&gt;Related work&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2023 | &lt;span style=&#34;color:#93003a&#34;&gt;BiB.Monitor Wohlbefinden 2023. Wie zufrieden ist die Bevölkerung Deutschlands?&lt;/span&gt; | with C. Katharina Spieß, Mara Barschkett, Volker Cihlar, Anna Dechant, Jean Philipp Décieux, Sabine Diabaté, Elke Lochinger, Nadja Milewski, Heiko Rüger, Sophia Schmitz, and Nico Stawarz | &lt;a href=&#34;https://a-genoni.github.io/uploads/9_Spie%C3%9F%20et%20al.%202023.%20BiB-Monitor-Wohlbefinden-Wie-zufrieden-ist-die-Bevoelkerung-in-Deutschland.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;span &gt;PDF&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Forthcoming | &lt;span style=&#34;color:#93003a&#34;&gt;Subjektives Wohlbefinden und demografische Ergeinisse im Lebenslauf.&lt;/span&gt; &lt;em&gt;WISTA - Wirtschaft und Statistik&lt;/em&gt; | with Volker Cihlar, Nadja Milewski, C. Katharina Spieß, and Nico Stawarz
&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work in progress | &lt;span style=&#34;color:#93003a&#34;&gt;Return migration and its impact on individuals&amp;rsquo; subjective well-being&lt;/span&gt; | with Martijn Hendriks and Nico Stawarz
&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work in progress | &lt;span style=&#34;color:#93003a&#34;&gt;Subjective well-being in the course of international migration&lt;/span&gt; | with Nico Stawarz, Andreas Ette, and Heiko Rüger | &lt;a href=&#34;https://a-genoni.github.io/uploads/3_Genoni%20et%20al.%20Poster%20Turning%20Gold.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;span &gt;Poster&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;https://a-genoni.github.io/current-work/mig-and-swb/&#34;&gt;More info&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
