<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Expectations | Andreas Genoni</title>
    <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/tag/expectations/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://a-genoni.github.io/tag/expectations/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Expectations</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://a-genoni.github.io/media/icon_hu36d72c3cf6f96053b96f9b849fe00da0_28466_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Expectations</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/tag/expectations/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>New blog post: Unmet expectations of immigrants and their consequences</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2023-11-04-nccr-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2023-11-04-nccr-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Highly qualified immigrants often tend to be under the radar of integration monitors. Due to their  qualifications and integration into local labour markets, we typically tend to assume they are fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, we find that some of them are not. Highly qualified immigrants often have high expectations about life abroad. This makes them particularly vulnerable to disappointment, giving them a hard time to feel welcome, accepted, and to form emotional bonds to their new home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://druedin.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Didier Ruedin&lt;/a&gt; (University of Neuchâtel) and I wrote a short blog post about it, and the potential consequences for both immigrants and host societies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can read the blog post online &lt;a href=&#34;https://nccr-onthemove.ch/blog/departure-for-the-promised-land-unmet-expectations-of-immigrants-and-their-consequences/?lang=de&amp;amp;utm_campaign=shareaholic&amp;amp;utm_medium=twitter&amp;amp;utm_source=socialnetwork&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, or directly download the &lt;a href=&#34;https://a-genoni.github.io/uploads/10_Genoni%20&amp;%20Ruedin.%202023.%20Departure%20for%20the%20Promised%20Land.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;span &gt;PDF&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Should I stay or should I go? Unmet migration expectations and out-migration of skilled recent immigrants</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/current-work/outmigration/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/current-work/outmigration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many knowledge-based economies are facing growing needs for skilled labour due to ageing populations, unsustainable fertility rates, and the ongoing green and digital transitions. Governments therefore increasingly depend on highly skilled immigrants in particular to respond to these challenges. However, highly skilled immigrants are probably more at risk of leaving their current country of residence compared to their lower-skilled counterparts. Empirical evidence suggests that highly skilled immigrants react comparably stronger to unmet migration expectations as their expectations to do well, fare well and be treated equally are particularly high, thus being more prone to be disappointed. Being highly qualified and more likely to cope with monetary and psychological consequences of migration decisions, such disappointment might lead them to pursue alternative career perspectives elsewhere in the global labour market, eventually making them leave the country. Here we analyse how unmet migration expectations of immigrants affect the probability of leaving their current destination country, and whether there are educational differences. We use panel data of recent immigrants to Switzerland from the Swiss Migration-Mobility (MMS) Survey and link them with administrative data to obtain information on immigrants’ whereabouts after being surveyed. Overall, we find that disappointed migration expectations increase the probability of immigrants to leave the country after the survey. Highly skilled immigrants are generally more likely to leave Switzerland than lower skilled immigrants. Importantly, however, we find that the stronger the migration disappointment, the greater is the likelihood of out-migration for highly skilled immigrants, making them particularly likely to leave.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The paradox of integration</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/project/paradox-of-integration/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/project/paradox-of-integration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Research and regular monitors about the integration of immigrants has typically looked at &amp;ldquo;objective&amp;rdquo; indicators of integration such as education, stable employment, language skills or income. In the past years, however, increasingly more attention has been given to the &amp;ldquo;inner life&amp;rdquo; of immigrants, referring to more &amp;ldquo;subjective&amp;rdquo; indicators of integration such as their emotional attachment to the new home, their feelings of belongingness to its society or their perceptions of discrimination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the continued publication of empirical studies on immigrants&amp;rsquo; subjective integration, an integration paradox has been revealed: Many of those immigrants who seem integrated in terms of their education or occupational status do not feel that they are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such a misalignment can be problematic because it may increase the likelihood of frustration, mental health issues, and emigration. But the seemingly better integrated are particularly valuable for receiving societies because they can play an important role in helping new arrivals to participate and incorporate into the institutions of the mainstream society. Furthermore, they are more efficiently deployable in the local labour market and less at risk from unemployment. These issues are particularly pressing in times when many developed countries face labour shortages and compete for talents globally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project bundles personal work on the integration paradox. It looks at different factors and mechanisms that contribute to this paradox, and tries to better understand the potential issues and consequences related to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;related-work&#34;&gt;Related work&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2022 | &lt;span style=&#34;color:#93003a&#34;&gt;Status and Ethnic Identity. A Study on First- and Second-Generation Migrants in Germany.&lt;/span&gt; Verlag Barbara Budrich | &lt;a href=&#34;https://a-genoni.github.io/publication/genoni-2022-status-and-ethnic-identity/&#34;&gt;Publication&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work in progress | &lt;span style=&#34;color:#93003a&#34;&gt;Unmet migration expectations and their consequences for the lives of immigrants&lt;/span&gt; | with Didier Ruedin | &lt;a href=&#34;https://a-genoni.github.io/current-work/expectations-and-attachment/&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;https://a-genoni.github.io/uploads/10_Genoni%20&amp;%20Ruedin.%202023.%20Departure%20for%20the%20Promised%20Land.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;span &gt;Blog post&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work in progress | &lt;span style=&#34;color:#93003a&#34;&gt;Reactive cosmopolitanism? Migrants&amp;rsquo; attachment to the EU as a response to social exclusion&lt;/span&gt; | with Nella Geurts | &lt;a href=&#34;https://a-genoni.github.io/current-work/reactive-cosmopolitanism/&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work in progress | &lt;span style=&#34;color:#93003a&#34;&gt;Should I stay or should I go? Unmet migration expectations and out-migration of skilled recent immigrants&lt;/span&gt; | with Didier Ruedin and Philippe Wanner | &lt;a href=&#34;https://a-genoni.github.io/current-work/outmigration/&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unmet migration expectations and their consequences for the lives of immigrants</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/current-work/expectations-and-attachment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/current-work/expectations-and-attachment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Migration research suggests that higher educated migrants report weaker
attachment to their destination country than their lower-educated counterparts.
This so-called integration paradox is probably caused by higher educated migrants
perceiving more discrimination in ambiguous or unfavourable situations. Here we
examine unmet expectations migrants have about their life abroad, experience of
discrimination, and how these account for educational differences in destination
attachment. We use cross-sectional and panel data of recent migrants to Switzerland
from the Swiss Migration-Mobility Survey, capturing unmet expectations with a
question on dissatisfaction with the migration decision. In line with the integration
paradox, we observe lower destination attachment among higher educated migrants
with unmet expectations. Although they more often report discrimination, this
does not explain their lower destination attachment within this group. Instead
of discrimination, adaptation problems matter. Higher educated migrants with unmet
expectations do not outperform their lower-educated counterparts on other integration
dimensions, particularly in social terms. These results indicate that migrants
do not necessarily link unmet expectations to discrimination. Migrants may be
optimistic and particularly vulnerable to disappointment but they can also mitigate
more detrimental consequences, because they are prepared for moving into an unfamiliar
environment despite lacking locally important resources.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
