<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Expectations | Andreas Genoni</title>
    <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/tag/expectations/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://a-genoni.github.io/tag/expectations/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Expectations</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://a-genoni.github.io/media/icon_hu36d72c3cf6f96053b96f9b849fe00da0_28466_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Expectations</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/tag/expectations/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Article review in the Frankfurter Allgemeine Zeitung (FAZ)</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2025-10-05-sf-article-in-faz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2025-10-05-sf-article-in-faz/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Well-educed immigrants arrive with high expectations&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/strong&gt; This is the title of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.faz.net/aktuell/wissen/geist-soziales/hochqualifizierte-migranten-warum-enttaeuschung-zur-abwanderung-fuehrt-accg-110714727.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;an article in the FAZ&lt;/a&gt;, written by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.soziologie.uni-konstanz.de/holzer/team/prof-boris-holzer-phd/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Boris Holzer (University of Konstanz)&lt;/a&gt;. He reviewed our paper on educational differences in immigrants&amp;rsquo; reactions to unmet migration expectations, which has recently been published in &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1093/sf/soaf157&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Social Forces&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, Holzer does a great job in reviewing our work, making it available to a broader audience beyond the research community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only thing I would like to point out is that our study focuses on immigrants&amp;rsquo; &lt;em&gt;reactions&lt;/em&gt; to unmet expectations, and not on how high these expectations are, as indicated by Holzer&amp;rsquo;s title. In our paper, we assume that particularly high expectations could be the reason for the the stronger reactions among highly educated immigrants, but we were unable to investigate this empirically. We still do not know whether highly educated immigrants indeed have higher migration expectations than their less-educated counterparts (and if so, in which areas). More research is needed to examine the potential educational inequalities in immigrants&amp;rsquo; expectations about life abroad.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When expectations backfire: Educational differences in declining destination attachment among recent immigrants</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/publication/genoni-ruedin-2025-expectations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/publication/genoni-ruedin-2025-expectations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;Suggested Citation:&lt;/strong&gt; Genoni, A.; Ruedin, D. (&lt;em&gt;forthcoming&lt;/em&gt;). When expectations backfire: Educational differences in declining destination attachment among recent immigrants. &lt;em&gt;Social Forces&lt;/em&gt;.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call for abstracts: Workshop on the integration paradox</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2024-11-20-cfp-ip-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2024-11-20-cfp-ip-workshop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;do-you-study-the-integration-paradox-ip&#34;&gt;Do you study the integration paradox (IP)?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If so, I kindly invite you to apply to participate in an international research workshop on the topic, which I co-organise in June &amp;lsquo;25 with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ru.nl/en/people/geurts-p&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Nella Geurts&lt;/a&gt; (Radboud University) and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.uu.nl/staff/CLavest&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Chloé Lavest&lt;/a&gt; (Utrecht University).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The integration paradox describes the phenomenon that seemingly well-integrated immigrants and their descendants often experience more discrimination and weaker belongingness to their new place of residence than their not-so-well-integrated counterparts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The IP literature has expanded significantly in recent years, but it still falls short on longitudinal perspectives and empirical evidence on the underlying mechanisms and scope of countries and migrant groups studied. We thus call for papers to further advance IP research and connect with other colleagues in the field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The workshop will take place &lt;strong&gt;at Utrecht University on June 18, 2025&lt;/strong&gt;, just before the Migration and Societal Change conference. We plan to produce a Special Issue based on the contributions presented during the workshop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more details, have a look at &lt;a href=&#34;https://a-genoni.github.io/uploads/CfP-workshop.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;span &gt;this information sheet&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-deadline-for-applications-is-february-1-2025&#34;&gt;The deadline for applications is February 1, 2025.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We look forward to receiving your submissions!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New blog post: Unmet expectations of immigrants and their consequences</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2023-11-04-nccr-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2023-11-04-nccr-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Highly qualified immigrants often tend to be under the radar of integration monitors. Due to their  qualifications and integration into local labour markets, we typically tend to assume they are fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, we find that some of them are not. Highly qualified immigrants often have high expectations about life abroad. This makes them particularly vulnerable to disappointment, giving them a hard time to feel welcome, accepted, and to form emotional bonds to their new home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://druedin.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Didier Ruedin&lt;/a&gt; (University of Neuchâtel) and I wrote a short blog post about it, and the potential consequences for both immigrants and host societies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can read the blog post online &lt;a href=&#34;https://nccr-onthemove.ch/blog/departure-for-the-promised-land-unmet-expectations-of-immigrants-and-their-consequences/?lang=de&amp;amp;utm_campaign=shareaholic&amp;amp;utm_medium=twitter&amp;amp;utm_source=socialnetwork&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, or directly download the &lt;a href=&#34;https://a-genoni.github.io/uploads/10_Genoni%20&amp;%20Ruedin.%202023.%20Departure%20for%20the%20Promised%20Land.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;span &gt;PDF&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The paradox of integration</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/project/paradox-of-integration/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/project/paradox-of-integration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Research and regular monitors about the integration of immigrants has typically looked at &amp;ldquo;objective&amp;rdquo; indicators of integration such as education, stable employment, language skills or income. In the past years, however, increasingly more attention has been given to the &amp;ldquo;inner life&amp;rdquo; of immigrants, referring to more &amp;ldquo;subjective&amp;rdquo; indicators of integration such as their emotional attachment to the new home, their feelings of belongingness to its society or their perceptions of discrimination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the continued publication of empirical studies on immigrants&amp;rsquo; subjective integration, an integration paradox has been revealed: Many of those immigrants who seem integrated in terms of their education or occupational status do not feel that they are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such a misalignment can be problematic because it may increase the likelihood of frustration, mental health issues, and emigration. But the seemingly better integrated are particularly valuable for receiving societies because they can play an important role in helping new arrivals to participate and incorporate into the institutions of the mainstream society. Furthermore, they are more efficiently deployable in the local labour market and less at risk from unemployment. These issues are particularly pressing in times when many developed countries face labour shortages and compete for talents globally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project bundles personal work on the integration paradox. It looks at different factors and mechanisms that contribute to this paradox, and tries to better understand the potential issues and consequences related to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;related-work&#34;&gt;Related work&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2025 | &lt;span style=&#34;color:#93003a&#34;&gt;When expectations backfire: Educational differences in declining destination attachment of recent immigrants&lt;/span&gt; | &lt;em&gt;Social Forces&lt;/em&gt; | with Didier Ruedin | &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1093/sf/soaf157&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Publication&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.31235/osf.io/srwbg_v3&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Preprint&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;https://a-genoni.github.io/uploads/10_Genoni%20&amp;%20Ruedin.%202023.%20Departure%20for%20the%20Promised%20Land.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;span &gt;Blog post&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2025 | &lt;span style=&#34;color:#93003a&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;This country needs to be more welcoming.&amp;rdquo; Warum die Schweiz internationale Fachkräfte verliert&lt;/span&gt; | &lt;em&gt;terra cognita&lt;/em&gt; | with Nils Witte | &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.terra-cognita.ch/fileadmin/user_upload/terracognita/documents/terra_cognita_41_bf.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Publication&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2022 | &lt;span style=&#34;color:#93003a&#34;&gt;Status and Ethnic Identity. A Study on First- and Second-Generation Migrants in Germany.&lt;/span&gt; Verlag Barbara Budrich | &lt;a href=&#34;https://a-genoni.github.io/publication/genoni-2022-status-and-ethnic-identity/&#34;&gt;Publication&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work in progress | &lt;span style=&#34;color:#93003a&#34;&gt;Reactive cosmopolitanism? Migrants&amp;rsquo; attachment to the EU as a response to social exclusion&lt;/span&gt; | with Nella Geurts | &lt;a href=&#34;https://a-genoni.github.io/current-work/reactive-cosmopolitanism/&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work in progress | &lt;span style=&#34;color:#93003a&#34;&gt;The interplay of education, religiosity and feelings of belonging among refugees in Germany&lt;/span&gt; | with Nadja Milewski and Lenore Sauer | &lt;a href=&#34;https://a-genoni.github.io/uploads/Milewski%20et%20al.%20Abstract.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;span &gt;Abstract&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work in progress | &lt;span style=&#34;color:#93003a&#34;&gt;Intersectionality in the impact of parenthood among immigrants in a high-income country: Unmet migration expectations among highly educated women and less-educated men
&lt;/span&gt; | with Natalie Nitsche | &lt;a href=&#34;https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2025-09-05-ecsr-and-minmig/&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
