<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Integration Paradox | Andreas Genoni</title>
    <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/tag/integration-paradox/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://a-genoni.github.io/tag/integration-paradox/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Integration Paradox</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://a-genoni.github.io/media/icon_hu36d72c3cf6f96053b96f9b849fe00da0_28466_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Integration Paradox</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/tag/integration-paradox/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>High hopes, high disappointment?</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2023-06-15-shp-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2023-06-15-shp-conference/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;what-happens-when-expectations-of-immigrants-about-live-abroad-do-not-meet-with-their-experiences&#34;&gt;What happens when expectations of immigrants about live abroad do not meet with their experiences?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I gave a talk about how unmet migration expectations influence the lives of immigrants. I started this work together with &lt;a href=&#34;https://druedin.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Didier Ruedin&lt;/a&gt; (University of Neuchâtel) last winter during my research stay at the Swiss National Center of Competence in Research (NCCR) on Migration and Mobility Studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using panel data of the Migration-Mobility Survey (MMS), we observed that unmet migration expectations hit harder on immigrants with tertiary education than immigrants with non-tertiary education. We found robust evidence for comparably stronger perceptions of discrimination (picture) and increased emotional disengagement with Switzerland. Stay tuned for the paper.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unmet migration expectations and their consequences for the lives of immigrants</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/current-work/expectations-and-attachment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/current-work/expectations-and-attachment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Migration research suggests that higher educated migrants report weaker
attachment to their destination country than their lower-educated counterparts.
This so-called integration paradox is probably caused by higher educated migrants
perceiving more discrimination in ambiguous or unfavourable situations. Here we
examine unmet expectations migrants have about their life abroad, experience of
discrimination, and how these account for educational differences in destination
attachment. We use cross-sectional and panel data of recent migrants to Switzerland
from the Swiss Migration-Mobility Survey, capturing unmet expectations with a
question on dissatisfaction with the migration decision. In line with the integration
paradox, we observe lower destination attachment among higher educated migrants
with unmet expectations. Although they more often report discrimination, this
does not explain their lower destination attachment within this group. Instead
of discrimination, adaptation problems matter. Higher educated migrants with unmet
expectations do not outperform their lower-educated counterparts on other integration
dimensions, particularly in social terms. These results indicate that migrants
do not necessarily link unmet expectations to discrimination. Migrants may be
optimistic and particularly vulnerable to disappointment but they can also mitigate
more detrimental consequences, because they are prepared for moving into an unfamiliar
environment despite lacking locally important resources.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Status and Ethnic Identity. A Study on First- and Second-Generation Migrants in Germany</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/publication/genoni-2022-status-and-ethnic-identity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/publication/genoni-2022-status-and-ethnic-identity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;Suggested Citation:&lt;/strong&gt; Genoni, A. (2022). &lt;em&gt;Status and Ethnic Identity. A Study on First- and Second-Generation Migrants in Germany.&lt;/em&gt; Verlag Barbara Budrich. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3224/84742575&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3224/84742575&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
