<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Integration Paradox | Andreas Genoni</title>
    <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/tag/integration-paradox/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://a-genoni.github.io/tag/integration-paradox/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Integration Paradox</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://a-genoni.github.io/media/icon_hu36d72c3cf6f96053b96f9b849fe00da0_28466_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Integration Paradox</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/tag/integration-paradox/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call for abstracts: Workshop on the integration paradox</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2024-11-20-cfp-ip-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2024-11-20-cfp-ip-workshop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;do-you-study-the-integration-paradox-ip&#34;&gt;Do you study the integration paradox (IP)?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If so, I kindly invite you to apply to participate in an international research workshop on the topic, which I co-organise in June &amp;lsquo;25 with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ru.nl/en/people/geurts-p&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Nella Geurts&lt;/a&gt; (Radboud University) and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.uu.nl/staff/CLavest&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Chloé Lavest&lt;/a&gt; (Utrecht University).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The integration paradox describes the phenomenon that seemingly well-integrated immigrants and their descendants often experience more discrimination and weaker belongingness to their new place of residence than their not-so-well-integrated counterparts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The IP literature has expanded significantly in recent years, but it still falls short on longitudinal perspectives and empirical evidence on the underlying mechanisms and scope of countries and migrant groups studied. We thus call for papers to further advance IP research and connect with other colleagues in the field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The workshop will take place &lt;strong&gt;at Utrecht University on June 18, 2025&lt;/strong&gt;, just before the Migration and Societal Change conference. We plan to produce a Special Issue based on the contributions presented during the workshop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more details, have a look at &lt;a href=&#34;https://a-genoni.github.io/uploads/CfP-workshop.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;span &gt;this information sheet&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-deadline-for-applications-is-february-1-2025&#34;&gt;The deadline for applications is February 1, 2025.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We look forward to receiving your submissions!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The conference summer goes on</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2024-09-22-sgs-and-ecsr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2024-09-22-sgs-and-ecsr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, almost everybody in the office had his/her conference trip this year. Thus, it was about time to head out myself to meet new people, chat with dear colleagues, and talk about ongoing projects to get some feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ssa-an-early-integration-paradox&#34;&gt;SSA: An early integration paradox?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first stop was Muttenz, a place close to Basel, where this years congress of the Swiss Sociological Association (SSA) took place. I had the opportunity to present an ongoing research project of &lt;a href=&#34;https://druedin.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Didier Ruedin&lt;/a&gt; (Université de Neuchâtel) and myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project uses longitudinal data of immigrants who recently arrived in Switzerland to explore the possibility of an &amp;ldquo;early&amp;rdquo; integration paradox as we refer to it. Scholars typically argue that the integration paradox, the phenomenon that seemingly integrated immigrants do not perceive themselves as integrated, actually reflects progress in integration. The reasoning behind this argument is that if immigrants and locals become more similar, the smaller differences become more salient and potentially problematic&amp;ndash;particularly for immigrants with visually distinct phenotypical markers or clothing. Clearly, this argument neglects the situation of recent immigrants who are at the beginning of their integration process. In our study, we investigate whether immigrants in this early stage might experience an integration paradox as well, and discuss why visually distinct immigrants of all people might be less affected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ecsr-should-i-stay-or-should-i-go-out-migration-of-recent-immigrants-to-switzerland&#34;&gt;ECSR: Should I stay or should I go? Out-migration of recent immigrants to Switzerland&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second stop was Barcelona, the capitol of Catalonia. The European Consortium for Sociological Research (ECSR) held its annual conference at the Universitat Pompeu Fabra. Besides getting inspired by great people and their projects, I had the honour to present a project of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.unige.ch/sciences-societe/ideso/membres/wanner/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Philippe Wanner&lt;/a&gt; (Université de Genève), &lt;a href=&#34;https://druedin.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Didier Ruedin&lt;/a&gt; (Université de Neuchâtel) and myself, in which we investigate whether unmet migration expectations increase the chance that immigrants leave the country to which they have just immigrated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We created an original panel data set by linking Swiss survey data with Swiss admin data. This way, we connected individual-level information of immigrants with registry information on their whereabouts after they have dropped out of the survey. This project takes a behavioural perspective on the integration paradox and investigates whether disappointment about life abroad not only weaken immigrants&amp;rsquo; emotional bonds to their destination country but also actually make them leave. Your hunch? Have a look at the findings &lt;a href=&#34;https://a-genoni.github.io/current-work/outmigration/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New research at the 16th ESA conference</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2024-08-27-esa-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2024-08-27-esa-conference/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While I took advantage of everyone being OUT of office to be productive IN the office, my dear colleagues Lenore and Nico presented ongoing mutual work in sunny Porto at the 16th ESA conference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;an-integration-paradox-among-the-most-religious-migrants&#34;&gt;An integration paradox among the most religious migrants?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The joint study with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bib.bund.de/DE/Institut/Mitarbeiter/Sauer/Sauer.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Lenore Sauer&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bib.bund.de/DE/Institut/Mitarbeiter/Milewski/Milewski.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Nadja Milewski&lt;/a&gt; investigates the relationship between migrants&amp;rsquo; level of education, degree of religiosity, and feelings of belongingness. We use data from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bib.bund.de/P/Transfar/EN/About/Transfar.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;TransFAR project&lt;/a&gt;, a BiB survey about Eritrean and Syrian recent refugees in Germany. In essence, our study examines whether the degree of religiosity is an explaining factor for the so-called integration paradox, the phenomenon that highly educated migrants do not really feel as integrated as one would expect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;return-of-the-failed-the-subjective-well-being-of-german-returnees&#34;&gt;Return of the failed? The subjective well-being of German returnees&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bib.bund.de/DE/Institut/Mitarbeiter/Stawarz/Stawarz.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Nico Stawarz&lt;/a&gt; presented the second study, in which we investigate shifts in the subjective well-being of German migrants in the course of their return to Germany. By looking at well-being trajectories of Germans with different return motives, we put contradicting theories about reasons for return migration to the test. Are returnees really those who lost the game of migration and travel back defeated, or could they be those who have successfully completed their stay abroad? This is collaborative work with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.martijnhendriks.net/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Martijn Hendriks&lt;/a&gt; (Erasmus University Rotterdam).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When expectations backfire: A longitudinal analysis on unmet migration expectations and destination attachment of recent immigrants to Switzerland</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/current-work/expectations-and-attachment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/current-work/expectations-and-attachment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Immigrants with higher levels of education tend to report more discrimination and a weaker attachment to their destination country than immigrants with lower levels of education. This so-called integration paradox is thought to occur because of two basic, mutually independent mechanisms:
(1) highly educated immigrants more often experience unmet migration expectations, and (2) show
stronger negative reactions when their expectations about their life abroad are not met. Existing research mainly focused on the first mechanism, and empirically tracing the second has been challenging
due to a lack of evidence comparing less- and more-educated immigrants’ reactions over time. Here,
we address this gap and examine how unmet migration expectations contribute to education-related
differences in destination attachment. Using panel data on recent immigrants to Switzerland from the
Swiss Migration-Mobility Survey (N = 5,242 immigrants and 13,890 observations, 2016-2022), we assessed the extent of unmet expectations and associated disappointment through a question on dissatisfaction with the decision to migrate. Consistent with theory, we found that increasingly negative
evaluations of pre-migration expectations were linked to reduced destination attachment, especially
for immigrants with higher levels of education. These results suggest a fundamental mechanism for
the emergence of the integration paradox, enhancing our understanding of immigrant integration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;Suggested citation:&lt;/strong&gt; Genoni, A. &amp;amp; Ruedin, D. (2024). When expectations backfire: A longitudinal analysis on unmet migration expectations and destination attachment of recent immigrants to Switzerland. &lt;em&gt;SocArXiv&lt;/em&gt;. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.31235/osf.io/srwbg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.31235/osf.io/srwbg&lt;/a&gt;.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is &#34;Reactive Cosmopolitanism&#34; a thing?</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2024-03-19-nella-in-wiesbaden/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2024-03-19-nella-in-wiesbaden/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the most exciting and enriching things in my profession is the chance to get to know great and like-minded people from all around the world, exchange ideas with them, learn from them, laugh with them and collaborate with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week, my dear colleague and friend &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ru.nl/en/people/geurts-p&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Nella Geurts&lt;/a&gt; (Radboud University, NL) visited me at the BiB in Wiesbaden to work on a mutual project based on our &lt;a href=&#34;https://gerps-project.de/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GERPS data&lt;/a&gt;. We had the chance to present our work in process in front of my BiB fellows and to get valuable feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You wonder what the project is about? Well, we do not want to already spoil too much at this point but you can already find an abstract &lt;a href=&#34;https://a-genoni.github.io/current-work/reactive-cosmopolitanism/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reactive cosmopolitanism? Migrants&#39; attachment to the EU as a response to social exclusion</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/current-work/reactive-cosmopolitanism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/current-work/reactive-cosmopolitanism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Empirical research has established an integration paradox (IP), describing that higher educated immigrants often feel more socially excluded and thus less attached to their destination country than their lower-educated counterparts. However, previous literature illustrates that conceptions of belonging can be derived from various levels, including supranational or more cosmopolitan ones such as Europe or the world as a whole. Combining these insights with studies on reactive ethnicity, we investigate to what extent identifying as cosmopolitan may be a reaction to stronger perceptions of social exclusion, and whether this differs for higher and lower educated immigrants. Our contribution to the IP literature is threefold: First, we explore how the integration paradox applies to supranational belonging by investigating belonging to Europe. Second, we use recent probability-based panel data by studying German migrants in over 130 countries worldwide. Third, by measuring feelings of being left out, we measure perceived social exclusion more broadly than by discrimination alone, arguing that also more implicit and indirect forms of exclusion affect immigrants’ feelings of belonging. Preliminary fixed effects analyses show that intensified feelings of being left out increase European attachment among immigrants in non-European countries, which is solely driven by higher educated immigrants, as lower educated immigrants show no such reactive behaviour. Overall, the study offers a new perspective on the drivers of cosmopolitanism by integrating insights from studies on the IP and reactive ethnicity, thereby also raising questions about the importance of national group membership for so-called world citizens.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Should I stay or should I go? Unmet migration expectations and out-migration of highly educated recent immigrants</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/current-work/outmigration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/current-work/outmigration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many knowledge-based economies are facing growing needs for skilled labour due to ageing populations, unsustainable fertility rates, and the ongoing green and digital transitions. Governments therefore increasingly depend on highly skilled immigrants in particular to respond to these challenges. However, highly skilled immigrants are probably more at risk of leaving their current country of residence compared to their lower-skilled counterparts. Empirical evidence suggests that highly skilled immigrants react comparably stronger to unmet migration expectations as their expectations to do well, fare well and be treated equally are particularly high, thus being more prone to be disappointed. Being highly qualified and more likely to cope with monetary and psychological consequences of migration decisions, such disappointment might lead them to pursue alternative career perspectives elsewhere in the global labour market, eventually making them leave the country. Here we analyse how unmet migration expectations of immigrants affect the probability of leaving their current destination country, and whether there are educational differences. We use panel data of recent immigrants to Switzerland from the Swiss Migration-Mobility (MMS) Survey and link them with administrative data to obtain information on immigrants’ whereabouts after being surveyed. Overall, we find that disappointed migration expectations increase the probability of immigrants to leave the country after the survey. Highly skilled immigrants are generally more likely to leave Switzerland than lower skilled immigrants. Importantly, however, we find that the stronger the migration disappointment, the greater is the likelihood of out-migration for highly skilled immigrants, making them particularly likely to leave.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New blog post: Unmet expectations of immigrants and their consequences</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2023-11-04-nccr-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2023-11-04-nccr-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Highly qualified immigrants often tend to be under the radar of integration monitors. Due to their  qualifications and integration into local labour markets, we typically tend to assume they are fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, we find that some of them are not. Highly qualified immigrants often have high expectations about life abroad. This makes them particularly vulnerable to disappointment, giving them a hard time to feel welcome, accepted, and to form emotional bonds to their new home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://druedin.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Didier Ruedin&lt;/a&gt; (University of Neuchâtel) and I wrote a short blog post about it, and the potential consequences for both immigrants and host societies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can read the blog post online &lt;a href=&#34;https://nccr-onthemove.ch/blog/departure-for-the-promised-land-unmet-expectations-of-immigrants-and-their-consequences/?lang=de&amp;amp;utm_campaign=shareaholic&amp;amp;utm_medium=twitter&amp;amp;utm_source=socialnetwork&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, or directly download the &lt;a href=&#34;https://a-genoni.github.io/uploads/10_Genoni%20&amp;%20Ruedin.%202023.%20Departure%20for%20the%20Promised%20Land.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;span &gt;PDF&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Expired] Call for Abstracts - IMISCOE Panel on unraveling the Integration Paradox</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2023-09-09-imiscoe-cfp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2023-09-09-imiscoe-cfp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deadline extended until October 11&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next year&amp;rsquo;s IMISCOE conference takes place in sunny Lisbon from July 2 to 5. Together with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ru.nl/en/people/geurts-p&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Nella Geurts&lt;/a&gt; (Radboud University), I&amp;rsquo;m submitting a panel with contributions that aim to unravel the Integration Paradox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you conduct research in this field and have something to contribute? We kindly invite you to submit your &lt;strong&gt;250 words abstract until October 11&lt;/strong&gt; to andreas.genoni(at)bib.bund.de. If you have any questions regarding the panel, don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to contact me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;panel-description&#34;&gt;Panel description&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In many immigration societies, researchers and policymakers still often evaluate the integration status of migrants in terms of more objective indicators such as residence duration, birth place, or education. Thus, when thinking of less and more successful integration, we tend to have specific groups of migrants in mind. However, a considerable number of studies has illustrated that exclusively focusing on more objective indicators of integration is problematic as they do not necessarily match with how migrants perceive their own integration. Opposing classic assimilation theories, various studies have found support for this so-called Integration Paradox where migrants, typically with a higher socio-economic position, feel more socially excluded and less belonging to the residence country. The panel aims to dive into this counterintuitive finding in various ways, for example by examining specific sub-groups, disentangling underlying mechanisms, and exploring new outcomes of interest. We aim to better understand the reasons for why seemingly integrated migrants do not feel like they are, and engage in discussions about individual and societal consequences that arise from this paradox.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The bigger they come, the harder they fall</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2023-08-28-knowledge-societies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2023-08-28-knowledge-societies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The fourth biannual conference of the Academy of Sociology took place at the University of Bern. I presented ongoing collaborative work about &lt;strong&gt;unmet migration expectations and why they are more consequential for higher than for lower educated immigrants&lt;/strong&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s an updated talk from that in Lausanne earlier this year. Email me if you&amp;rsquo;d like to know more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is collaborative work with my colleague &lt;a href=&#34;https://druedin.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Didier Ruedin&lt;/a&gt; from the University of Neuchâtel. We thank all participants for their constructive feedback!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High hopes, high disappointment?</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2023-06-15-shp-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2023-06-15-shp-conference/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;what-happens-when-expectations-of-immigrants-about-live-abroad-do-not-meet-with-their-experiences&#34;&gt;What happens when expectations of immigrants about live abroad do not meet with their experiences?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I gave a talk about how unmet migration expectations influence the lives of immigrants. I started this work together with &lt;a href=&#34;https://druedin.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Didier Ruedin&lt;/a&gt; (University of Neuchâtel) last winter during my research stay at the Swiss National Center of Competence in Research (NCCR) on Migration and Mobility Studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using panel data of the Migration-Mobility Survey (MMS), we observed that unmet migration expectations hit harder on immigrants with tertiary education than immigrants with non-tertiary education. We found robust evidence for comparably stronger perceptions of discrimination (picture) and increased emotional disengagement with Switzerland. Stay tuned for the paper.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Status and Ethnic Identity. A Study on First- and Second-Generation Migrants in Germany</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/publication/genoni-2022-status-and-ethnic-identity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/publication/genoni-2022-status-and-ethnic-identity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;Suggested Citation:&lt;/strong&gt; Genoni, A. (2022). &lt;em&gt;Status and Ethnic Identity. A Study on First- and Second-Generation Migrants in Germany.&lt;/em&gt; Verlag Barbara Budrich. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3224/84742575&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3224/84742575&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
