<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data visualisation | Andreas Genoni</title>
    <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/tag/data-visualisation/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://a-genoni.github.io/tag/data-visualisation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Data visualisation</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://a-genoni.github.io/media/icon_hu36d72c3cf6f96053b96f9b849fe00da0_28466_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Data visualisation</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/tag/data-visualisation/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ever wondered about the movement of people around the world?</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2023-12-18-global-flow-2.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2023-12-18-global-flow-2.0/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-global-flow-of-people-20&#34;&gt;The Global Flow of People 2.0&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this interactive tool, you can find out which places people around the world leave and which places they move to. You can either look at global migration in general, at global refugees in particular, or at the movement of people within Germany.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The interactive visualisation is part of an international project that I managed and coordinated. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bib.bund.de/DE/Institut/Mitarbeiter/Sander/Sander.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Nikola Sander&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bib.bund.de/DE/Institut/Mitarbeiter/Kolowa/Kolowa.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Tamilwai Kolowa&lt;/a&gt; (both BiB), Tina Frank, Clemens Schrammel (both University of Arts Linz) and Ramon Bauer (Statistics Vienna) were involved.
&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;1100&#34; name=&#34;iframe&#34; src=&#34;https://www.bib.bund.de/EN/Service/Tools/Migration/iframe/iframe.html&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
You can find out more about the data and the visualisation on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bib.bund.de/EN/Service/Tools/Migration/Globalflows.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;main site of our project&lt;/a&gt;. There, you will also find more download material such as the underlying data and R scripts to create static versions of the interactive circular migration plot.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Round table on dataviz in policy relevant research</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2020-07-06-dataviz-round-table/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2020-07-06-dataviz-round-table/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;what-makes-good-dataviz-for-policy-relevant-research&#34;&gt;What makes good dataviz for policy relevant research?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data visualisation plays an important role in communicating research to others. This is especially the
case in policy-making processes, where researchers want to avoid misinterpretation of empirical evidence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;knowing-our-stuff&#34;&gt;Knowing our stuff&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Participants agreed that for being able to communicate research through visualisations,
researchers first have to understand what they are doing. This may seem like a no-brainer but
researchers have to make themselves familiar with the data they are working with, and,
depending on the discipline, with the mechanisms that contribute to the observed patterns in the data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Researchers are responsible for their products, and responsibility can best be borne by knowledgeable people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;finding-the-middle-ground&#34;&gt;Finding the middle ground&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The challenge that most participants of the round table addressed was to deal
with trade-offs between simplicity and complexity. Policy makers want numbers
to quantify things but a single number often provides incomplete information of complex
relationships in the data. Dataviz helps to attach more information to numbers but
visualising data properly takes more time&amp;mdash;and time is a limited resource in policy-making processes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
