<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2 | Andreas Genoni</title>
    <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/publication-type/2/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://a-genoni.github.io/publication-type/2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>2</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://a-genoni.github.io/media/icon_hu36d72c3cf6f96053b96f9b849fe00da0_28466_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>2</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/publication-type/2/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>When expectations backfire: A longitudinal analysis on unmet migration expectations and destination attachment of recent immigrants to Switzerland</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/current-work/expectations-and-attachment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/current-work/expectations-and-attachment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Immigrants with higher levels of education tend to report more discrimination and a weaker attachment to their destination country than immigrants with lower levels of education. This so-called integration paradox is thought to occur because of two basic, mutually independent mechanisms:
(1) highly educated immigrants more often experience unmet migration expectations, and (2) show
stronger negative reactions when their expectations about their life abroad are not met. Existing research mainly focused on the first mechanism, and empirically tracing the second has been challenging
due to a lack of evidence comparing less- and more-educated immigrants’ reactions over time. Here,
we address this gap and examine how unmet migration expectations contribute to education-related
differences in destination attachment. Using panel data on recent immigrants to Switzerland from the
Swiss Migration-Mobility Survey (N = 5,242 immigrants and 13,890 observations, 2016-2022), we assessed the extent of unmet expectations and associated disappointment through a question on dissatisfaction with the decision to migrate. Consistent with theory, we found that increasingly negative
evaluations of pre-migration expectations were linked to reduced destination attachment, especially
for immigrants with higher levels of education. These results suggest a fundamental mechanism for
the emergence of the integration paradox, enhancing our understanding of immigrant integration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;Suggested citation:&lt;/strong&gt; Genoni, A. &amp;amp; Ruedin, D. (2024). When expectations backfire: A longitudinal analysis on unmet migration expectations and destination attachment of recent immigrants to Switzerland. &lt;em&gt;SocArXiv&lt;/em&gt;. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.31235/osf.io/srwbg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.31235/osf.io/srwbg&lt;/a&gt;.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International migration and shifts in subjective well-being. A longitudinal study using German panel data</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/publication/genoni-et-al-2024-int-mig-and-swb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/publication/genoni-et-al-2024-int-mig-and-swb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;Suggested Citation:&lt;/strong&gt; Genoni, A.; Stawarz, N.; Ette, A.; Rüger, H. (2024). International migration and shifts in subjective well-being: A longitudinal study using German panel data. &lt;em&gt;Migration Studies&lt;/em&gt;, 1-19. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1093/migration/mnae008&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1093/migration/mnae008&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reactive cosmopolitanism? Migrants&#39; attachment to the EU as a response to social exclusion</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/current-work/reactive-cosmopolitanism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/current-work/reactive-cosmopolitanism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Empirical research has established an integration paradox (IP), describing that higher educated immigrants often feel more socially excluded and thus less attached to their destination country than their lower-educated counterparts. However, previous literature illustrates that conceptions of belonging can be derived from various levels, including supranational or more cosmopolitan ones such as Europe or the world as a whole. Combining these insights with studies on reactive ethnicity, we investigate to what extent identifying as cosmopolitan may be a reaction to stronger perceptions of social exclusion, and whether this differs for higher and lower educated immigrants. Our contribution to the IP literature is threefold: First, we explore how the integration paradox applies to supranational belonging by investigating belonging to Europe. Second, we use recent probability-based panel data by studying German migrants in over 130 countries worldwide. Third, by measuring feelings of being left out, we measure perceived social exclusion more broadly than by discrimination alone, arguing that also more implicit and indirect forms of exclusion affect immigrants’ feelings of belonging. Preliminary fixed effects analyses show that intensified feelings of being left out increase European attachment among immigrants in non-European countries, which is solely driven by higher educated immigrants, as lower educated immigrants show no such reactive behaviour. Overall, the study offers a new perspective on the drivers of cosmopolitanism by integrating insights from studies on the IP and reactive ethnicity, thereby also raising questions about the importance of national group membership for so-called world citizens.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Should I stay or should I go? Unmet migration expectations and out-migration of skilled recent immigrants</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/current-work/outmigration/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/current-work/outmigration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many knowledge-based economies are facing growing needs for skilled labour due to ageing populations, unsustainable fertility rates, and the ongoing green and digital transitions. Governments therefore increasingly depend on highly skilled immigrants in particular to respond to these challenges. However, highly skilled immigrants are probably more at risk of leaving their current country of residence compared to their lower-skilled counterparts. Empirical evidence suggests that highly skilled immigrants react comparably stronger to unmet migration expectations as their expectations to do well, fare well and be treated equally are particularly high, thus being more prone to be disappointed. Being highly qualified and more likely to cope with monetary and psychological consequences of migration decisions, such disappointment might lead them to pursue alternative career perspectives elsewhere in the global labour market, eventually making them leave the country. Here we analyse how unmet migration expectations of immigrants affect the probability of leaving their current destination country, and whether there are educational differences. We use panel data of recent immigrants to Switzerland from the Swiss Migration-Mobility (MMS) Survey and link them with administrative data to obtain information on immigrants’ whereabouts after being surveyed. Overall, we find that disappointed migration expectations increase the probability of immigrants to leave the country after the survey. Highly skilled immigrants are generally more likely to leave Switzerland than lower skilled immigrants. Importantly, however, we find that the stronger the migration disappointment, the greater is the likelihood of out-migration for highly skilled immigrants, making them particularly likely to leave.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Status transition in the educational system and well-being of migrant adolescents in cross-national comparison</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/publication/nauck-genoni-2019-status-transition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/publication/nauck-genoni-2019-status-transition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Suggested Citation:
Nauck, B., Genoni, A. (2019). Status transition in the educational system and well-being of migrant adolescents in cross-national comparison. &lt;em&gt;Zeitschrift für Erziehungswissenschaft 22&lt;/em&gt;(S1), 47–69. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/s11618-019-00887-z&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/s11618-019-00887-z&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
