<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Identity | Andreas Genoni</title>
    <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/tag/identity/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://a-genoni.github.io/tag/identity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Identity</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://a-genoni.github.io/media/icon_hu36d72c3cf6f96053b96f9b849fe00da0_28466_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Identity</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/tag/identity/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cultural distance and immigrant adjustment</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/current-work/cd-and-adjustment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/current-work/cd-and-adjustment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The cultural distance (CD) between the country of origin and destination
country of migrants has long been considered important for adjustment in
international migration. Past research has mainly followed a cost perspective,
pointing to rising costs in adjustment with increasing CD, postulating a negative
linear relationship. Following this logic, previous studies overlooked potential
benefits of CD for adjustment. We address this gap by taking a more differentiated
perspective on CD and adjustment. Using unique probability-based survey data on
German migrants in 38 destination countries with a maximum length of
stay of 36 months, we examined different CD-levels and their consequences for
adjustment. We ran multilevel regressions for sociocultural and psychological
adjustment. Importantly, our findings indicate that the CD effect on adjustment
is not linear but clearly resembles an inverted-U shape for both adjustment
dimensions. This result challenges the cost perspective and suggests an “optimal”
range of intermediate CD as most beneficial for recent migrants’ adjustment. We
conclude that the prevailing view on the consequences of CD for migrant adjustment
holds true for very large CDs, but it underestimates the challenges for culturally
close migrants and overlooks that a certain level of cultural dissimilarity can
facilitate migrants’ adjustment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Individual consequences of international migration</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/project/consequences-of-international-migration/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/project/consequences-of-international-migration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A question that I am particularly interested in is how international migration impacts the lives of immigrants. This question is a tough one, because it is one of cause and effect and requires unique data to address it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, it is not sufficient to compare individuals after their move abroad with non-migrated individuals in their home country, because differences between these groups may be the result of specific characteristics of the individuals within the two groups. If we imagine that migration can be a stressful live event, individuals who move abroad might be healthier and more resilient than individuals who stay put, because migration would otherwise not be feasible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, if researchers would find physical and mental health advantages among migrants, it would be unclear whether they made this discovery because migrants are genuinely healthier and happier, or because migration itself may have contributed to their increased health and happiness. By the way, the thought of migration as a potentially positive life event is not far-fetched at all, because migration may not only be stressful but also open up individual opportunities to develop and thrive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apparently, addressing the question of cause and effect of migration places an extremely high demand on data. They have to be longitudinal and must include actual migration events. This enables researchers to observe individuals before, during and after their move abroad, and to compare these different stages with each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But how can researchers find and survey individuals who &lt;strong&gt;will&lt;/strong&gt; move abroad during the time of a planned panel survey? Unless researchers are blessed with foresight, they have to come up with a promising strategy. Luckily, my colleagues at the BiB did so. The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gerps-project.de/gerps/EN/Project/Project.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;German Emigration and Remigration Panel Study (GERPS)&lt;/a&gt; meets these high data demands. Following Germans who shortly moved abroad or returned to Germany before the survey started, we collected data of a internationally highly mobile population with a high probability of being internationally mobile again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The work listed below is based on these unique data. It aims to tighten the boundaries of causal inference by shedding light on the actual consequences of international migration for immigrants&amp;rsquo; lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;related-work&#34;&gt;Related work&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work in progress | &lt;span style=&#34;color:#93003a&#34;&gt;International migration and the subjective well-being of internationally mobile individuals&lt;/span&gt; | with Nico Stawarz, Andreas Ette, and Heiko Rüger | &lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;more info&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The paradox of integration</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/project/paradox-of-integration/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/project/paradox-of-integration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Research and regular monitors about the integration of immigrants has typically looked at &amp;ldquo;objective&amp;rdquo; indicators of integration such as education, stable employment, language skills or income. In the past years, however, increasingly more attention has been given to the &amp;ldquo;inner life&amp;rdquo; of immigrants, referring to more &amp;ldquo;subjective&amp;rdquo; indicators of integration such as their emotional attachment to the new home, their feelings of belongingness to its society or their perceptions of discrimination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the continued publication of empirical studies on immigrants&amp;rsquo; subjective integration, an integration paradox has been revealed: Many of those immigrants who seem integrated in terms of their education or occupational status do not feel that they are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such a misalignment can be problematic because it may increase the likelihood of frustration, mental health issues, and emigration. But the seemingly better integrated are particularly valuable for receiving societies because they can play an important role in helping new arrivals to participate and incorporate into the institutions of the mainstream society. Furthermore, they are more efficiently deployable in the local labour market and less at risk from unemployment. These issues are particularly pressing in times when many developed countries face labour shortages and compete for talents globally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project bundles personal work on the integration paradox. It looks at different factors and mechanisms that contribute to this paradox, and tries to better understand the potential issues and consequences related to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;related-work&#34;&gt;Related work&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2022 | &lt;span style=&#34;color:#93003a&#34;&gt;Status and Ethnic Identity. A Study on First- and Second-Generation Migrants in Germany.&lt;/span&gt; Verlag Barbara Budrich | &lt;a href=&#34;https://a-genoni.github.io/publication/genoni-2022-status-and-ethnic-identity/&#34;&gt;publication&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work in progress | &lt;span style=&#34;color:#93003a&#34;&gt;Unmet migration expectations and their consequences for the lives of immigrants&lt;/span&gt; | with Didier Ruedin | &lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;more info&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
