<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>GERPS | Andreas Genoni</title>
    <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/tag/gerps/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://a-genoni.github.io/tag/gerps/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>GERPS</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://a-genoni.github.io/media/icon_hu36d72c3cf6f96053b96f9b849fe00da0_28466_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>GERPS</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/tag/gerps/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is it all about the costs? Cultural distance and adjustment of recent migrants</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/publication/genoni-et-al-2023-is-it-all-about-costs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/publication/genoni-et-al-2023-is-it-all-about-costs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;Suggested citation:&lt;/strong&gt; Genoni, A.; Décieux, J. P.; Murdock, E. (2023). Is it all about the costs? Cultural distance and adjustment of recent migrants. &lt;em&gt;SocArXiv&lt;/em&gt;. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.31235/osf.io/uskq9&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.31235/osf.io/uskq9&lt;/a&gt;.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does international migration make people happy?</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2023-07-07-migration-and-swb/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2023-07-07-migration-and-swb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I gave a lightning talk at the BiB&amp;rsquo;s Turning Gold conference about &lt;strong&gt;shifts in subjective well-being in the course of international migration&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;mdash;a study with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bib.bund.de/EN/Institute/Staff/Stawarz/Stawarz.html;jsessionid=CA1C73D7435F153D69470FF104799585.intranet662&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Nico Stawarz&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bib.bund.de/DE/Institut/Mitarbeiter/Ette/Ette.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Andreas Ette&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bib.bund.de/DE/Institut/Mitarbeiter/Rueger/Rueger.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Heiko Rüger&lt;/a&gt; (all BiB).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using unique longitudinal data that includes actual migration events (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gerps-project.de/gerps/EN/Home.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GERPS&lt;/a&gt;), we find robust evidence that the subjective well-being of internationally mobile individuals increases notably with their move abroad (picture).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International migration and subjective well-being</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/current-work/mig-and-swb/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/current-work/mig-and-swb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In many economically highly-developed countries, a relevant proportion
of the population migrates across national boundaries every year. For these
individuals, migrating abroad not only comes with advantages (e.g. monetary
returns) but also with potential pitfalls, because migration is accompanied by
profound changes in everyday life. However, only few and mainly cross-sectional
studies about individuals’ migration expierences exist, analysing the effects
of migration on their quality of life. This study addresses these lacunae and
investigates shifts in subjective well-being (SWB) of internationally mobile
German citizens. We apply fixed effects (FE) panel regression models to data of
the German Emigration and Remigration Panel Study (GERPS). To observe SWB in
the course of migration, we draw on a sample of repeat migrants—Germans who
returned to Germany shortly before the panel and migrated again across international
borders during the panel. As counterfactuals, we focus on Germans who returned
to Germany shortly before the panel but stayed there. Overall life satisfaction
is used as an SWB-indicator, which corresponds to a global assessment of one’s
life situation. In sum, our analyses reveal a happiness dip before migration as
well as an increased and relatively stable SWB at the pre-migration baseline
level in the first two years after migration.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
