<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Publication | Andreas Genoni</title>
    <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/category/publication/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://a-genoni.github.io/category/publication/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Publication</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://a-genoni.github.io/media/icon_hu36d72c3cf6f96053b96f9b849fe00da0_28466_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Publication</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/category/publication/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>New publication about the well-being of international migrants</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2024-03-20-publication-swb/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2024-03-20-publication-swb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Moving abroad can both be a challenging but also rewarding event in people&amp;rsquo;s lives. Internationally mobile people often leave relevant others and material belongings behind and often find themselves in an unfamiliar environment, within which they sometimes even face reservations from the local population. As if all of this is not enough, moving abroad needs careful planning ahead, ensuring that crossing national borders and changing one&amp;rsquo;s place of residence is in accordance with all involved countries&amp;rsquo; laws. Sounds quite stressful!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With so much stuff going on in the process of emigration, it&amp;rsquo;s hard to keep track of how well international migrants are doing overall. Clearly, just looking at how their income changes with the move doesn&amp;rsquo;t do justice to everything that is going on. We thus took a different approach an looked at shifts in the subjective well-being of individuals that are in the process of leaving their country to life somewhere else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This study is unique as it is one of the first that is following people throughout their whole emigration process. This is made possible with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://gerps-project.de/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;German Emigration and Remigration Panel Study (GERPS)&lt;/a&gt;, a longitudinal study that is representative of the internationally mobile German population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-results-in-a-nutshell&#34;&gt;The results in a nutshell&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are able to show a general increase in people&amp;rsquo;s well-being during their emigration. Importantly, this increase is not short-term as well-being remains elevated in the first years after migration. The extent of the change in well-being thereby systematically depends on negotiation processes related to the migration decision: accompanying individuals (so-called trailing partners) experience the smallest gains in well-being compared to those who made the migration decision jointly with their partner or those who were the driving force behind the migration (so-called leading partners). Being unconstrained by a partner, singles even showed more pronounced increases in their well-being.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-can-we-learn-from-the-study&#34;&gt;What can we learn from the study?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The study suggests that, despite its associated challenges, international migration is generally positive for people from affluent societies. The increasing internationalization of education and careers, along with subsequent high return rates, supports policies that promote international mobility as recurring events in people&amp;rsquo;s lives. However, the findings also highlight potential social inequalities between those who migrate internationally and those who don&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;get-the-article&#34;&gt;Get the article&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in reading the whole article, you can head over to &lt;a href=&#34;https://academic.oup.com/migration/advance-article-abstract/doi/10.1093/migration/mnae008/7630980?redirectedFrom=fulltext#supplementary-data&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Migration Studies&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to get in touch with me if you lack access.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;credits&#34;&gt;Credits&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article is collaborative work with my dear colleagues &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bib.bund.de/DE/Institut/Mitarbeiter/Stawarz/Stawarz.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Nico Stawarz&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bib.bund.de/DE/Institut/Mitarbeiter/Ette/Ette.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Andreas Ette&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bib.bund.de/DE/Institut/Mitarbeiter/Rueger/Rueger.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Heiko Rüger&lt;/a&gt; from the Federal Institute for Population Research (BiB).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New blog post: Unmet expectations of immigrants and their consequences</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2023-11-04-nccr-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2023-11-04-nccr-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Highly qualified immigrants often tend to be under the radar of integration monitors. Due to their  qualifications and integration into local labour markets, we typically tend to assume they are fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, we find that some of them are not. Highly qualified immigrants often have high expectations about life abroad. This makes them particularly vulnerable to disappointment, giving them a hard time to feel welcome, accepted, and to form emotional bonds to their new home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://druedin.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Didier Ruedin&lt;/a&gt; (University of Neuchâtel) and I wrote a short blog post about it, and the potential consequences for both immigrants and host societies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can read the blog post online &lt;a href=&#34;https://nccr-onthemove.ch/blog/departure-for-the-promised-land-unmet-expectations-of-immigrants-and-their-consequences/?lang=de&amp;amp;utm_campaign=shareaholic&amp;amp;utm_medium=twitter&amp;amp;utm_source=socialnetwork&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, or directly download the &lt;a href=&#34;https://a-genoni.github.io/uploads/10_Genoni%20&amp;%20Ruedin.%202023.%20Departure%20for%20the%20Promised%20Land.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;span &gt;PDF&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The BiB Well-Being Monitor 2023</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2023-10-05-wb-monitor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2023-10-05-wb-monitor/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The BiB has a new flagship product: The BiB Well-Being Monitor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Its idea is to inform the public and policy makers about the well-being of the German population. Among existing transfer publications on well-being, the monitor stands out with its focus on the most dissatisfied and satisfied people in the population. Going beyond the average well-being level of groups makes the report particularly useful for policy makers to maintain the well-being of the highly satisfied and improve the well-being of the most vulnerable groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The monitor is written in German but I give you a quick summary about what we&amp;rsquo;ve found for the migrant population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;children-of-immigrants-are-the-least-satisfied&#34;&gt;Children of immigrants are the least satisfied&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compared to immigrants and the resident population, children of immigrants are the least satisfied. They more often report particularly low satisfaction with their life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take a look at the figure above: The children of immigrants&amp;ndash;or the people from the so-called second generation&amp;ndash;are shown in the middle. They have the highest share of people who are less satisfied (39.7%, represented by the blueish bar), and the lowest share of people who are very satisfied (12.1%, represented by the greenish bar).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These shares particularly contrast those in the immigrant population&amp;ndash;the so-called first generation&amp;ndash;, which you see on the far right in the figure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;smaller-differences-bigger-impact&#34;&gt;Smaller differences, bigger impact&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Strange, isn&amp;rsquo;t it? The second generation, whose living conditions are more similar to those of the resident population, are less satisfied than the first generation who immigrated themselves and have to find their way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most plausible explanations for this difference is that first- and second-generation migrants tend to use different reference points against which they evaluate their life and satisfaction with it. While immigrants more likely compare their current life abroad to their past in the origin country or non-migrated peers, children of immigrants tend to compare their situation more likely to that of the resident population. For immigrants, the comparison often feels positive, knowing that they left for a (hopefully) better future. For their children however, the comparison is often to their disadvantage, revealing the admittedly smaller but still existing inequalities that clash with unmet desires of same life chances and equal treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;more-information&#34;&gt;More information&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can download the Monitor &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bib.bund.de/Publikation/2023/BiB-Monitor-2023-Wohlbefinden-Wie-zufrieden-ist-die-Bevoelkerung-in-Deutschland.html?nn=1219342&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. (German only)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.freda-panel.de/FReDA/EN/Startseite.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, you find more information on the FReDA Panel, the data on which the Monitor is based. (English and German)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
