<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>MMS | Andreas Genoni</title>
    <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/tag/mms/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://a-genoni.github.io/tag/mms/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>MMS</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://a-genoni.github.io/media/icon_hu36d72c3cf6f96053b96f9b849fe00da0_28466_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>MMS</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/tag/mms/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>When expectations backfire: A longitudinal analysis on unmet migration expectations and destination attachment of recent immigrants to Switzerland</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/current-work/expectations-and-attachment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/current-work/expectations-and-attachment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Immigrants with higher levels of education tend to report more discrimination and a weaker attachment to their destination country than immigrants with lower levels of education. This so-called integration paradox is thought to occur because of two basic, mutually independent mechanisms:
(1) highly educated immigrants more often experience unmet migration expectations, and (2) show
stronger negative reactions when their expectations about their life abroad are not met. Existing research mainly focused on the first mechanism, and empirically tracing the second has been challenging
due to a lack of evidence comparing less- and more-educated immigrants’ reactions over time. Here,
we address this gap and examine how unmet migration expectations contribute to education-related
differences in destination attachment. Using panel data on recent immigrants to Switzerland from the
Swiss Migration-Mobility Survey (N = 5,242 immigrants and 13,890 observations, 2016-2022), we assessed the extent of unmet expectations and associated disappointment through a question on dissatisfaction with the decision to migrate. Consistent with theory, we found that increasingly negative
evaluations of pre-migration expectations were linked to reduced destination attachment, especially
for immigrants with higher levels of education. These results suggest a fundamental mechanism for
the emergence of the integration paradox, enhancing our understanding of immigrant integration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;Suggested citation:&lt;/strong&gt; Genoni, A. &amp;amp; Ruedin, D. (2024). When expectations backfire: A longitudinal analysis on unmet migration expectations and destination attachment of recent immigrants to Switzerland. &lt;em&gt;SocArXiv&lt;/em&gt;. doi: &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.31235/osf.io/srwbg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.31235/osf.io/srwbg&lt;/a&gt;.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The bigger they come, the harder they fall</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2023-08-28-knowledge-societies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2023-08-28-knowledge-societies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The fourth biannual conference of the Academy of Sociology took place at the University of Bern. I presented ongoing collaborative work about &lt;strong&gt;unmet migration expectations and why they are more consequential for higher than for lower educated immigrants&lt;/strong&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s an updated talk from that in Lausanne earlier this year. Email me if you&amp;rsquo;d like to know more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is collaborative work with my colleague &lt;a href=&#34;https://druedin.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Didier Ruedin&lt;/a&gt; from the University of Neuchâtel. We thank all participants for their constructive feedback!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High hopes, high disappointment?</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2023-06-15-shp-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2023-06-15-shp-conference/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;what-happens-when-expectations-of-immigrants-about-live-abroad-do-not-meet-with-their-experiences&#34;&gt;What happens when expectations of immigrants about live abroad do not meet with their experiences?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I gave a talk about how unmet migration expectations influence the lives of immigrants. I started this work together with &lt;a href=&#34;https://druedin.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Didier Ruedin&lt;/a&gt; (University of Neuchâtel) last winter during my research stay at the Swiss National Center of Competence in Research (NCCR) on Migration and Mobility Studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using panel data of the Migration-Mobility Survey (MMS), we observed that unmet migration expectations hit harder on immigrants with tertiary education than immigrants with non-tertiary education. We found robust evidence for comparably stronger perceptions of discrimination (picture) and increased emotional disengagement with Switzerland. Stay tuned for the paper.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Should I stay or should I go? Unmet migration expectations and out-migration of skilled recent immigrants</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/current-work/outmigration/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/current-work/outmigration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many knowledge-based economies are facing growing needs for skilled labour due to ageing populations, unsustainable fertility rates, and the ongoing green and digital transitions. Governments therefore increasingly depend on highly skilled immigrants in particular to respond to these challenges. However, highly skilled immigrants are probably more at risk of leaving their current country of residence compared to their lower-skilled counterparts. Empirical evidence suggests that highly skilled immigrants react comparably stronger to unmet migration expectations as their expectations to do well, fare well and be treated equally are particularly high, thus being more prone to be disappointed. Being highly qualified and more likely to cope with monetary and psychological consequences of migration decisions, such disappointment might lead them to pursue alternative career perspectives elsewhere in the global labour market, eventually making them leave the country. Here we analyse how unmet migration expectations of immigrants affect the probability of leaving their current destination country, and whether there are educational differences. We use panel data of recent immigrants to Switzerland from the Swiss Migration-Mobility (MMS) Survey and link them with administrative data to obtain information on immigrants’ whereabouts after being surveyed. Overall, we find that disappointed migration expectations increase the probability of immigrants to leave the country after the survey. Highly skilled immigrants are generally more likely to leave Switzerland than lower skilled immigrants. Importantly, however, we find that the stronger the migration disappointment, the greater is the likelihood of out-migration for highly skilled immigrants, making them particularly likely to leave.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
