<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Talk | Andreas Genoni</title>
    <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/category/talk/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://a-genoni.github.io/category/talk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Talk</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://a-genoni.github.io/media/icon_hu36d72c3cf6f96053b96f9b849fe00da0_28466_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Talk</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/category/talk/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research workshop on unraveling the Integration Paradox</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2025-06-23-workshop-uu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2025-06-23-workshop-uu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After coming back from my research stay in Canberra at the beginning of June, I had to prepare for a research workshop on the Integration Paradox which I co-hosted together with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.uu.nl/staff/CLavest&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Chloé Lavest&lt;/a&gt; (Utrecht University) and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ru.nl/en/people/geurts-p&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Nella Geurts &lt;/a&gt; (Radboud University). The workshop took place in lovely Utrecht, right before the second Migration and Societal Change (MSC) Conference at Utrecht University. This was no coincidence of course. The idea was to join forces and attract as many great people to Utrecht as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Workshop summary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were really unlucky. First, the employees of the dutch railroad company NS went on strike on the day of arrival. While one person from Germany couldn&amp;rsquo;t make it to the workshop because of that, the other international participants struggled quite a bit to get to Utrecht. Then, at the workshop day itself, we realised that protesters have occupied the building in which our workshop should have taken place. Thanks to Chloé, a last-minute room change was possible. Now, we only had to direct everyone to the new place shortly before the event kicked-off, re-order catering and set up the IT at the new venue. Sounds stressful? Well, at least I can say that we were no longer stressed about conducting the workshop itself&amp;ndash;which was a huge success against all odds!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had the pleasure to listen to nine interesting presentations that dived into the mechanisms underlying the Integration Paradox. Among others, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.soziologie.uni-konstanz.de/diehl/team/prof-dr-claudia-diehl/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Claudia Diehl&lt;/a&gt; (University of Konstanz) talked about perceived wage unfairness, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.compas.ox.ac.uk/people/sanne-van-oosten&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Sanne van Oosten&lt;/a&gt; (Oxford University) about reasons for heightened discrimination awareness among highly educated immigrants, and Ben van Enk about the Integration Paradox from a country-level perspective, focusing on EU countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I presented ongoing work with &lt;a href=&#34;https://druedin.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Didier Ruedin&lt;/a&gt; (University of Neuchâtel), in which we show that the Integration Paradox isn’t just about highly educated immigrants. Less-educated immigrants also play a role. And depending on how recognisable someone is as an immigrant, the paradox tends to emerge at different stages of their stay in the country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conference summary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the MSC Conference, we organised a roundtable on the Integration Paradox to communicate our insights from the workshop to a wider audience, discuss the current state of research and future avenues within our field. Nella, Chloé, Claudia and I were interested to engage with the audience to hear their opinion on the status quo and promising further research. We were surprised how many people attended our roundtable and actively participated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What was the bottom line? The unraveling of the Integration Paradox is ongoing! As a consequence, the field is united by this one term, which at the same time is becoming increasingly obsolete due to the progress in research. Who knows, maybe we need to find a new title for a potential next workshop&amp;hellip; ;-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A big shout out to everyone who was there! Without you, this event wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have made much sense.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research stay at the Australian National University (ANU)</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2025-05-06-stay-at-anu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2025-05-06-stay-at-anu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Have you ever heard of Canberra? It is the planned capital city of Australia, which was built in the early 20th century. It is also the place where you can find the Australian National University (ANU), where I visited the School of Demography at the ANU College of Arts &amp;amp; Social Sciences in May 2025.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My colleague &lt;a href=&#34;https://researchportalplus.anu.edu.au/en/persons/natalie-nitsche&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Natalie Nitsche&lt;/a&gt; works at ANU. She is a demographer and sociologist with whom I&amp;rsquo;m collaborating in a project on the impact of first-time parenthood on immigrants&amp;rsquo; socio-emotional life at the intersection of gender and education. We had the opportunity to present our paper at the regular colloquium and received great feedback that helped us further developing the project during my stay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned for more input later this year.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inaugural conference of the Population Research Center (PRC) at Uni Zurich</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2025-01-25-prc-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2025-01-25-prc-conference/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The recently founded Population Research Center (PRC) at the University of Zurich organised an inaugural conference, inviting population scientists across disciplines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These were an inspiring two days. I&amp;rsquo;m always surprised by the constructive feedback, lively discussions and exchange at interdisciplinary conferences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took the chance to talk about an ongoing research project of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.unige.ch/sciences-societe/ideso/membres/wanner/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Philippe Wanner&lt;/a&gt; (Université de Genève), &lt;a href=&#34;https://druedin.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Didier Ruedin&lt;/a&gt; (Université de Neuchâtel) and myself, in which we investigate whether unmet migration expectations increase the chance that immigrants leave the country to which they have just immigrated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We created an original panel data set by linking Swiss survey data with Swiss admin data. This way, we connected individual-level information of immigrants with registry information on their whereabouts after they have dropped out of the survey. This project takes a behavioural perspective on the integration paradox and investigates whether disappointment about life abroad not only weaken immigrants&amp;rsquo; emotional bonds to their destination country but also actually make them leave. Your hunch? Have a look at the findings &lt;a href=&#34;https://a-genoni.github.io/current-work/outmigration/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I already presented this project at last year&amp;rsquo;s ECSR in Barcelona. However, I took the time in-between the conferences to update the manuscript and the talk. I would like to thank all participants for great feedback. Can&amp;rsquo;t wait until the first full draft of the paper.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The conference summer goes on</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2024-09-22-sgs-and-ecsr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2024-09-22-sgs-and-ecsr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, almost everybody in the office had his/her conference trip this year. Thus, it was about time to head out myself to meet new people, chat with dear colleagues, and talk about ongoing projects to get some feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ssa-an-early-integration-paradox&#34;&gt;SSA: An early integration paradox?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first stop was Muttenz, a place close to Basel, where this years congress of the Swiss Sociological Association (SSA) took place. I had the opportunity to present an ongoing research project of &lt;a href=&#34;https://druedin.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Didier Ruedin&lt;/a&gt; (Université de Neuchâtel) and myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project uses longitudinal data of immigrants who recently arrived in Switzerland to explore the possibility of an &amp;ldquo;early&amp;rdquo; integration paradox as we refer to it. Scholars typically argue that the integration paradox, the phenomenon that seemingly integrated immigrants do not perceive themselves as integrated, actually reflects progress in integration. The reasoning behind this argument is that if immigrants and locals become more similar, the smaller differences become more salient and potentially problematic&amp;ndash;particularly for immigrants with visually distinct phenotypical markers or clothing. Clearly, this argument neglects the situation of recent immigrants who are at the beginning of their integration process. In our study, we investigate whether immigrants in this early stage might experience an integration paradox as well, and discuss why visually distinct immigrants of all people might be less affected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ecsr-should-i-stay-or-should-i-go-out-migration-of-recent-immigrants-to-switzerland&#34;&gt;ECSR: Should I stay or should I go? Out-migration of recent immigrants to Switzerland&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second stop was Barcelona, the capitol of Catalonia. The European Consortium for Sociological Research (ECSR) held its annual conference at the Universitat Pompeu Fabra. Besides getting inspired by great people and their projects, I had the honour to present a project of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.unige.ch/sciences-societe/ideso/membres/wanner/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Philippe Wanner&lt;/a&gt; (Université de Genève), &lt;a href=&#34;https://druedin.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Didier Ruedin&lt;/a&gt; (Université de Neuchâtel) and myself, in which we investigate whether unmet migration expectations increase the chance that immigrants leave the country to which they have just immigrated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We created an original panel data set by linking Swiss survey data with Swiss admin data. This way, we connected individual-level information of immigrants with registry information on their whereabouts after they have dropped out of the survey. This project takes a behavioural perspective on the integration paradox and investigates whether disappointment about life abroad not only weaken immigrants&amp;rsquo; emotional bonds to their destination country but also actually make them leave. Your hunch? Have a look at the findings &lt;a href=&#34;https://a-genoni.github.io/current-work/outmigration/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New research at the 16th ESA conference</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2024-08-27-esa-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2024-08-27-esa-conference/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While I took advantage of everyone being OUT of office to be productive IN the office, my dear colleagues Lenore and Nico presented ongoing mutual work in sunny Porto at the 16th ESA conference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;an-integration-paradox-among-the-most-religious-migrants&#34;&gt;An integration paradox among the most religious migrants?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The joint study with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bib.bund.de/DE/Institut/Mitarbeiter/Sauer/Sauer.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Lenore Sauer&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bib.bund.de/DE/Institut/Mitarbeiter/Milewski/Milewski.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Nadja Milewski&lt;/a&gt; investigates the relationship between migrants&amp;rsquo; level of education, degree of religiosity, and feelings of belongingness. We use data from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bib.bund.de/P/Transfar/EN/About/Transfar.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;TransFAR project&lt;/a&gt;, a BiB survey about Eritrean and Syrian recent refugees in Germany. In essence, our study examines whether the degree of religiosity is an explaining factor for the so-called integration paradox, the phenomenon that highly educated migrants do not really feel as integrated as one would expect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;return-of-the-failed-the-subjective-well-being-of-german-returnees&#34;&gt;Return of the failed? The subjective well-being of German returnees&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bib.bund.de/DE/Institut/Mitarbeiter/Stawarz/Stawarz.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Nico Stawarz&lt;/a&gt; presented the second study, in which we investigate shifts in the subjective well-being of German migrants in the course of their return to Germany. By looking at well-being trajectories of Germans with different return motives, we put contradicting theories about reasons for return migration to the test. Are returnees really those who lost the game of migration and travel back defeated, or could they be those who have successfully completed their stay abroad? This is collaborative work with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.martijnhendriks.net/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Martijn Hendriks&lt;/a&gt; (Erasmus University Rotterdam).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is &#34;Reactive Cosmopolitanism&#34; a thing?</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2024-03-19-nella-in-wiesbaden/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2024-03-19-nella-in-wiesbaden/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the most exciting and enriching things in my profession is the chance to get to know great and like-minded people from all around the world, exchange ideas with them, learn from them, laugh with them and collaborate with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week, my dear colleague and friend &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ru.nl/en/people/geurts-p&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Nella Geurts&lt;/a&gt; (Radboud University, NL) visited me at the BiB in Wiesbaden to work on a mutual project based on our &lt;a href=&#34;https://gerps-project.de/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GERPS data&lt;/a&gt;. We had the chance to present our work in process in front of my BiB fellows and to get valuable feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You wonder what the project is about? Well, we do not want to already spoil too much at this point but you can already find an abstract &lt;a href=&#34;https://a-genoni.github.io/current-work/reactive-cosmopolitanism/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The bigger they come, the harder they fall</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2023-08-28-knowledge-societies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2023-08-28-knowledge-societies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The fourth biannual conference of the Academy of Sociology took place at the University of Bern. I presented ongoing collaborative work about &lt;strong&gt;unmet migration expectations and why they are more consequential for higher than for lower educated immigrants&lt;/strong&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s an updated talk from that in Lausanne earlier this year. Email me if you&amp;rsquo;d like to know more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is collaborative work with my colleague &lt;a href=&#34;https://druedin.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Didier Ruedin&lt;/a&gt; from the University of Neuchâtel. We thank all participants for their constructive feedback!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does international migration make people happy?</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2023-07-07-migration-and-swb/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2023-07-07-migration-and-swb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I gave a lightning talk at the BiB&amp;rsquo;s Turning Gold conference about &lt;strong&gt;shifts in subjective well-being in the course of international migration&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;mdash;a study with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bib.bund.de/EN/Institute/Staff/Stawarz/Stawarz.html;jsessionid=CA1C73D7435F153D69470FF104799585.intranet662&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Nico Stawarz&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bib.bund.de/DE/Institut/Mitarbeiter/Ette/Ette.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Andreas Ette&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bib.bund.de/DE/Institut/Mitarbeiter/Rueger/Rueger.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Heiko Rüger&lt;/a&gt; (all BiB).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using unique longitudinal data that includes actual migration events (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gerps-project.de/gerps/EN/Home.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;GERPS&lt;/a&gt;), we find robust evidence that the subjective well-being of internationally mobile individuals increases notably with their move abroad (picture).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High hopes, high disappointment?</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2023-06-15-shp-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2023-06-15-shp-conference/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;what-happens-when-expectations-of-immigrants-about-live-abroad-do-not-meet-with-their-experiences&#34;&gt;What happens when expectations of immigrants about live abroad do not meet with their experiences?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I gave a talk about how unmet migration expectations influence the lives of immigrants. I started this work together with &lt;a href=&#34;https://druedin.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Didier Ruedin&lt;/a&gt; (University of Neuchâtel) last winter during my research stay at the Swiss National Center of Competence in Research (NCCR) on Migration and Mobility Studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using panel data of the Migration-Mobility Survey (MMS), we observed that unmet migration expectations hit harder on immigrants with tertiary education than immigrants with non-tertiary education. We found robust evidence for comparably stronger perceptions of discrimination (picture) and increased emotional disengagement with Switzerland. Stay tuned for the paper.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
