<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Belonging | Andreas Genoni</title>
    <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/tag/belonging/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://a-genoni.github.io/tag/belonging/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Belonging</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://a-genoni.github.io/media/icon_hu36d72c3cf6f96053b96f9b849fe00da0_28466_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Belonging</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/tag/belonging/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>New blog post: Unmet expectations of immigrants and their consequences</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2023-11-04-nccr-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2023-11-04-nccr-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Highly qualified immigrants often tend to be under the radar of integration monitors. Due to their  qualifications and integration into local labour markets, we typically tend to assume they are fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, we find that some of them are not. Highly qualified immigrants often have high expectations about life abroad. This makes them particularly vulnerable to disappointment, giving them a hard time to feel welcome, accepted, and to form emotional bonds to their new home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://druedin.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Didier Ruedin&lt;/a&gt; (University of Neuchâtel) and I wrote a short blog post about it, and the potential consequences for both immigrants and host societies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can read the blog post online &lt;a href=&#34;https://nccr-onthemove.ch/blog/departure-for-the-promised-land-unmet-expectations-of-immigrants-and-their-consequences/?lang=de&amp;amp;utm_campaign=shareaholic&amp;amp;utm_medium=twitter&amp;amp;utm_source=socialnetwork&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, or directly download the &lt;a href=&#34;https://a-genoni.github.io/uploads/10_Genoni%20&amp;%20Ruedin.%202023.%20Departure%20for%20the%20Promised%20Land.pdf&#34;&gt;&lt;span&gt;PDF&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Expired] Call for Abstracts - IMISCOE Panel on unraveling the Integration Paradox</title>
      <link>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2023-09-09-imiscoe-cfp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://a-genoni.github.io/post/2023-09-09-imiscoe-cfp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deadline extended until October 11&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next year&amp;rsquo;s IMISCOE conference takes place in sunny Lisbon from July 2 to 5. Together with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ru.nl/en/people/geurts-p&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Nella Geurts&lt;/a&gt; (Radboud University), I&amp;rsquo;m submitting a panel with contributions that aim to unravel the Integration Paradox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you conduct research in this field and have something to contribute? We kindly invite you to submit your &lt;strong&gt;250 words abstract until October 11&lt;/strong&gt; to andreas.genoni(at)bib.bund.de. If you have any questions regarding the panel, don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to contact me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;panel-description&#34;&gt;Panel description&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In many immigration societies, researchers and policymakers still often evaluate the integration status of migrants in terms of more objective indicators such as residence duration, birth place, or education. Thus, when thinking of less and more successful integration, we tend to have specific groups of migrants in mind. However, a considerable number of studies has illustrated that exclusively focusing on more objective indicators of integration is problematic as they do not necessarily match with how migrants perceive their own integration. Opposing classic assimilation theories, various studies have found support for this so-called Integration Paradox where migrants, typically with a higher socio-economic position, feel more socially excluded and less belonging to the residence country. The panel aims to dive into this counterintuitive finding in various ways, for example by examining specific sub-groups, disentangling underlying mechanisms, and exploring new outcomes of interest. We aim to better understand the reasons for why seemingly integrated migrants do not feel like they are, and engage in discussions about individual and societal consequences that arise from this paradox.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
